{
    "title": "The Market Forces of Supply and Demand",
    "icon": "<svg xmlns=\"http://www.w3.org/2000/svg\" class=\"h-8 w-8\" fill=\"none\" viewBox=\"0 0 24 24\" stroke=\"currentColor\" stroke-width=\"2\"><path stroke-linecap=\"round\" stroke-linejoin=\"round\" d=\"M19 11H5m14 0a2 2 0 012 2v6a2 2 0 01-2 2H5a2 2 0 01-2-2v-6a2 2 0 012-2m14 0V9a2 2 0 00-2-2M5 11V9a2 2 0 012-2m0 0V5a2 2 0 012-2h6a2 2 0 012 2v2M7 7h10\" /></svg>",
    "sectors": {
        "sector1": {
            "title": "Multiple Choice",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "Multiple Choice",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The two words most often used by economists are",
                    "options": [
                        "prices and quantities.",
                        "resources and allocation.",
                        "supply and demand.",
                        "efficiency and equity."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply and demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "Multiple Choice",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The two words economists use most often are",
                    "options": [
                        "inflation and trade.",
                        "supply and demand.",
                        "competition and prices.",
                        "markets and equilibrium."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply and demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "Multiple Choice",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The forces that make market economies work are",
                    "options": [
                        "work and leisure.",
                        "politics and religion.",
                        "supply and demand.",
                        "taxes and government spending."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply and demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "Multiple Choice",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In a market economy, supply and demand determine",
                    "options": [
                        "both the quantity of each good produced and the price at which it is sold.",
                        "the quantity of each good produced but not the price at which it is sold.",
                        "the price at which each good is sold but not the quantity of each good produced.",
                        "neither the quantity of each good produced nor the price at which it is sold."
                    ],
                    "answer": "both the quantity of each good produced and the price at which it is sold.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "Multiple Choice",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In a market economy, supply and demand are important because they",
                    "options": [
                        "play a critical role in the allocation of the economy's scarce resources.",
                        "determine how much of each good gets produced.",
                        "can be used to predict the impact on the economy of various events and policies.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "Multiple Choice",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In a market economy, supply and demand are important because they",
                    "options": [
                        "are direct policy tools used by government agencies to regulate the economy.",
                        "illustrate when an market is in equilibrium, but they are not helpful when a market is out of equilibrium.",
                        "can be used to predict the impact on the economy of various events and policies.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "can be used to predict the impact on the economy of various events and policies.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "Multiple Choice",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In a market economy,",
                    "options": [
                        "supply determines demand and demand, in turn, determines prices.",
                        "demand determines supply and supply, in turn, determines prices.",
                        "the allocation of scarce resources determines prices and prices, in turn, determine supply and demand.",
                        "supply and demand determine prices and prices, in turn, allocate the economy's scarce resources."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply and demand determine prices and prices, in turn, allocate the economy's scarce resources.",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        },
        "sector2": {
            "title": "Markets And Competition",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "Buyers determine supply, and sellers determine demand.",
                        "Buyers determine demand, and sellers determine supply.",
                        "Buyers determine both demand and supply.",
                        "Sellers determine both demand and supply."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Buyers determine demand, and sellers determine supply.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The demand for a good or service is determined by",
                    "options": [
                        "those who buy the good or service.",
                        "the government.",
                        "those who sell the good or service.",
                        "both those who buy and those who sell the good or service."
                    ],
                    "answer": "those who buy the good or service.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The supply of a good or service is determined by",
                    "options": [
                        "those who buy the good or service.",
                        "the government.",
                        "those who sell the good or service.",
                        "both those who buy and those who sell the good or service."
                    ],
                    "answer": "those who sell the good or service.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A group of buyers and sellers of a particular good or service is called a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "coalition.",
                        "economy.",
                        "market.",
                        "competition."
                    ],
                    "answer": "market.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a market for a good or service to exist, there must be a",
                    "options": [
                        "group of buyers and sellers.",
                        "specific time and place at which the good or service is traded.",
                        "high degree of organization present.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "group of buyers and sellers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is an example of a market?",
                    "options": [
                        "a gas station",
                        "a garage sale",
                        "a barber shop",
                        "All of the above are examples of markets."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are examples of markets.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The market for ice cream is a",
                    "options": [
                        "monopolistic market.",
                        "highly competitive market.",
                        "highly organized market.",
                        "Both b) and c) are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "highly competitive market.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 8,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Most markets in the economy are",
                    "options": [
                        "markets in which sellers, rather than buyers, control the price of the product.",
                        "markets in which buyers, rather than sellers, control the price of the product.",
                        "perfectly competitive.",
                        "highly competitive."
                    ],
                    "answer": "highly competitive.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 9,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A market includes",
                    "options": [
                        "buyers only.",
                        "sellers only.",
                        "both buyers and sellers.",
                        "the place where transactions occur but not the people involved."
                    ],
                    "answer": "both buyers and sellers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 10,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is not an example of a market?",
                    "options": [
                        "A small town has only one seller of electricity.",
                        "In the United States, a sick person cannot legally purchase a kidney.",
                        "In Florida, there are many buyers and sellers of key lime pie.",
                        "The availability of Internet shopping has expanded the clothing choices for buyers who do not live near large cities."
                    ],
                    "answer": "In the United States, a sick person cannot legally purchase a kidney.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 11,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In a competitive market, the price of a product",
                    "options": [
                        "is determined by buyers, and the quantity of the product produced is determined by sellers.",
                        "is determined by sellers, and the quantity of the product produced is determined by buyers.",
                        "and the quantity of the product produced are both determined by sellers.",
                        "None of the above is correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "None of the above is correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 12,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In a competitive market, the quantity of a product produced and the price of the product are determined by",
                    "options": [
                        "buyers.",
                        "sellers.",
                        "both buyers and sellers.",
                        "None of the above is correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "both buyers and sellers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 13,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In a competitive market, the quantity of a product produced and the price of the product are determined by",
                    "options": [
                        "a single buyer.",
                        "a single seller.",
                        "one buyer and one seller working together.",
                        "all buyers and all sellers."
                    ],
                    "answer": "all buyers and all sellers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 14,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A competitive market is a market in which",
                    "options": [
                        "an auctioneer helps set prices and arrange sales.",
                        "there are only a few sellers.",
                        "the forces of supply and demand do not apply.",
                        "no individual buyer or seller has any significant impact on the market price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "no individual buyer or seller has any significant impact on the market price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 15,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A competitive market is one in which there",
                    "options": [
                        "is only one seller, but there are many buyers.",
                        "are many sellers, and each seller has the ability to set the price of his product.",
                        "are many sellers, and they compete with one another in such a way that some sellers are always being forced out of the market.",
                        "are so many buyers and so many sellers that each has a negligible impact on the price of the product."
                    ],
                    "answer": "are so many buyers and so many sellers that each has a negligible impact on the price of the product.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 16,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Assume Diana buys computers in a competitive market. It follows that",
                    "options": [
                        "Diana has a limited number of sellers to turn to when she buys a computer.",
                        "Diana will find herself negotiating with sellers whenever she buys a computer.",
                        "if Diana buys a large number of computers, the price of computers will rise noticeably.",
                        "None of the above is correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "None of the above is correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 17,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In a competitive market, each seller has limited control over the price of his product because",
                    "options": [
                        "other sellers are offering similar products.",
                        "buyers exert more control over the price than do sellers.",
                        "these markets are highly regulated by the government.",
                        "sellers usually agree to set a common price that will allow each seller to earn a comfortable profit."
                    ],
                    "answer": "other sellers are offering similar products.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 18,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a competitive market,",
                    "options": [
                        "a seller can always increase her profit by raising the price of her product.",
                        "if a seller charges more than the going price, buyers will go elsewhere to make their purchases.",
                        "a seller often charges less than the going price to increase sales and profit.",
                        "a single buyer can influence the price of the product but only when purchasing from several sellers in a short period of time."
                    ],
                    "answer": "if a seller charges more than the going price, buyers will go elsewhere to make their purchases.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 19,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a seller in a competitive market chooses to charge more than the going price, then",
                    "options": [
                        "the sellers' profits must increase.",
                        "the owners of the raw materials used in production would raise the prices for the raw materials.",
                        "other sellers would also raise their prices.",
                        "buyers will make purchases from other sellers."
                    ],
                    "answer": "buyers will make purchases from other sellers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 20,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In competitive markets, buyers",
                    "options": [
                        "are price takers, but sellers are price setters.",
                        "are price setters, but sellers are price takers.",
                        "and sellers are price takers.",
                        "and sellers are price setters."
                    ],
                    "answer": "and sellers are price takers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 21,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The term price takers refers to buyers and sellers in",
                    "options": [
                        "perfectly competitive markets.",
                        "monopolistic markets.",
                        "markets that are regulated by the government.",
                        "markets in which buyers cannot buy all they want and/or sellers cannot sell all they want."
                    ],
                    "answer": "perfectly competitive markets.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 22,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In competitive markets,",
                    "options": [
                        "firms produce identical products.",
                        "no individual buyer can influence the market price.",
                        "no individual seller can influence the market price.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 23,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In competitive markets, which of the following is not correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "Firms produce identical products.",
                        "No individual buyer can influence the market price.",
                        "Some sellers can set prices.",
                        "Buyers are price takers."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Some sellers can set prices.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 24,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In competitive markets,",
                    "options": [
                        "firms produce identical products.",
                        "buyers can influence the market price more easily than sellers.",
                        "markets are more likely to be in equilibrium.",
                        "sellers are price setters."
                    ],
                    "answer": "firms produce identical products.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 25,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The highest form of competition is called",
                    "options": [
                        "absolute competition.",
                        "cutthroat competition.",
                        "perfect competition.",
                        "market competition."
                    ],
                    "answer": "perfect competition.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 26,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The highest form of competition is called",
                    "options": [
                        "arbitrage.",
                        "monopolistic competition.",
                        "equilibrium.",
                        "perfect competition."
                    ],
                    "answer": "perfect competition.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 27,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of a perfectly competitive market?",
                    "options": [
                        "Different sellers sell identical products.",
                        "There are many sellers.",
                        "Sellers must accept the price the market determines.",
                        "All of the above are characteristics of a perfectly competitive market."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are characteristics of a perfectly competitive market.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 28,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of a perfectly competitive market?",
                    "options": [
                        "Sellers set the price of the product.",
                        "There are many sellers.",
                        "Buyers must accept the price the market determines.",
                        "All of the above are characteristics of a perfectly competitive market."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Sellers set the price of the product.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 29,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Buyers and sellers who have no influence on market price are referred to as",
                    "options": [
                        "market pawns.",
                        "monopolists.",
                        "price takers.",
                        "price setters."
                    ],
                    "answer": "price takers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 30,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When all market participants are price takers who have no influence over prices, the markets have",
                    "options": [
                        "only a few buyers and sellers.",
                        "numerous sellers but only a few buyers.",
                        "numerous buyers but only a few sellers.",
                        "numerous buyers and sellers."
                    ],
                    "answer": "numerous buyers and sellers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 31,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If buyers and sellers in a certain market are price takers, then individually",
                    "options": [
                        "they have no influence on market price.",
                        "they have some influence on market price but that influence is limited.",
                        "buyers will be able to find prices lower than those determined in the market.",
                        "sellers will find it difficult to sell all they want to sell at the market price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "they have no influence on market price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 32,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In a perfectly competitive market, at the market price, buyers",
                    "options": [
                        "cannot buy all they want, and sellers cannot sell all they want.",
                        "cannot buy all they want, but sellers can sell all they want.",
                        "can buy all they want, but sellers cannot sell all they want.",
                        "can buy all they want, and sellers can sell all they want."
                    ],
                    "answer": "can buy all they want, and sellers can sell all they want.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 33,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An example of a perfectly competitive market would be the",
                    "options": [
                        "cable TV market.",
                        "soybean market.",
                        "breakfast cereal market.",
                        "shampoo market."
                    ],
                    "answer": "soybean market.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 34,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An example of a perfectly competitive market would be the market for",
                    "options": [
                        "tennis racquets.",
                        "pizza.",
                        "garbage collection.",
                        "wheat."
                    ],
                    "answer": "wheat.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 35,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An example of a perfectly competitive market would be the market for",
                    "options": [
                        "electricity.",
                        "soybeans.",
                        "coffee shops.",
                        "restaurants."
                    ],
                    "answer": "soybeans.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 36,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is the least likely to be a competitive market?",
                    "options": [
                        "ice cream",
                        "soybeans",
                        "cable television",
                        "new houses"
                    ],
                    "answer": "cable television",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 37,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Assume the market for tennis balls is perfectly competitive. When one tennis ball producer exits the market,",
                    "options": [
                        "the price of tennis balls increases.",
                        "the price of tennis balls decreases.",
                        "the price of tennis balls does not change.",
                        "there is no longer a market for tennis balls."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the price of tennis balls does not change.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 38,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Assume the market for pork is perfectly competitive. When one pork buyer exits the market,",
                    "options": [
                        "the price of pork increases.",
                        "the price of pork decreases.",
                        "the price of pork does not change.",
                        "there is no longer a market for pork."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the price of pork does not change.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 39,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is not a reason perfect competition is a useful simplification, despite the diversity of market types we find in the world?",
                    "options": [
                        "Perfectly competitive markets are the easiest to analyze because everyone participating in the market takes the price as given by market conditions.",
                        "Some degree of competition is present in most markets.",
                        "There are many buyers and many sellers in all types of markets.",
                        "Many of the lessons that we learn by studying supply and demand under perfect competition apply in more complicated markets as well."
                    ],
                    "answer": "There are many buyers and many sellers in all types of markets.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 40,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a firm is a price taker, it operates in a",
                    "options": [
                        "competitive market.",
                        "monopoly market.",
                        "oligopoly market.",
                        "monopolistically competitive market."
                    ],
                    "answer": "competitive market.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 41,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A monopoly is a market with one",
                    "options": [
                        "seller, and that seller is a price taker.",
                        "seller, and that seller sets the price.",
                        "buyer, and that buyer is a price taker.",
                        "buyer, and that buyer sets the price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "seller, and that seller sets the price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 42,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following would most likely serve as an example of a monopoly?",
                    "options": [
                        "a bakery in a large city",
                        "a bank in a large city",
                        "a local cable television company",
                        "a small group of corn farmers"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a local cable television company",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 43,
                    "topic": "Markets And Competition",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following would most likely serve as an example of a monopoly?",
                    "options": [
                        "a restaurant in a large city",
                        "a dry cleaners in a large city",
                        "a local gas station",
                        "a local electrical company"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a local electrical company",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        },
        "sector3": {
            "title": "Demand",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The quantity demanded of a good is the amount that buyers are",
                    "options": [
                        "willing to purchase.",
                        "willing and able to purchase.",
                        "willing, able, and need to purchase.",
                        "able to purchase."
                    ],
                    "answer": "willing and able to purchase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An increase in quantity demanded",
                    "options": [
                        "results in a movement downward and to the right along a demand curve.",
                        "results in a movement upward and to the left along a demand curve.",
                        "shifts the demand curve to the left.",
                        "shifts the demand curve to the right."
                    ],
                    "answer": "results in a movement downward and to the right along a demand curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A decrease in quantity demanded",
                    "options": [
                        "results in a movement downward and to the right along a demand curve.",
                        "results in a movement upward and to the left along a demand curve.",
                        "shifts the demand curve to the left.",
                        "shifts the demand curve to the right."
                    ],
                    "answer": "results in a movement upward and to the left along a demand curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A movement upward and to the left along a demand curve is called a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in demand.",
                        "decrease in demand.",
                        "decrease in quantity demanded.",
                        "increase in quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A movement downward and to the right along a demand curve is called a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in demand.",
                        "decrease in demand.",
                        "decrease in quantity demanded.",
                        "increase in quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase in quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An increase in the price of a good will",
                    "options": [
                        "increase demand.",
                        "decrease demand.",
                        "increase quantity demanded.",
                        "decrease quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A decrease in the price of a good will",
                    "options": [
                        "increase demand.",
                        "decrease demand.",
                        "increase quantity demanded.",
                        "decrease quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 8,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When the price of a good or service changes,",
                    "options": [
                        "the supply curve shifts in the opposite direction.",
                        "the demand curve shifts in the opposite direction.",
                        "the demand curve shifts in the same direction.",
                        "there is a movement along a given demand curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "there is a movement along a given demand curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 9,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A decrease in the price of a good would",
                    "options": [
                        "increase the supply of the good.",
                        "increase the quantity demanded of the good.",
                        "give producers an incentive to produce more to keep profits from falling.",
                        "shift the supply curve for the good to the left."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase the quantity demanded of the good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 10,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-1. The movement from point A to point B on the graph shows",
                    "options": [
                        "a decrease in demand.",
                        "an increase in demand.",
                        "a decrease in quantity demanded.",
                        "an increase in quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "an increase in quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 11,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-1. The movement from point A to point B on the graph is caused by",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in price.",
                        "a decrease in price.",
                        "a decrease in the price of a substitute good.",
                        "an increase in income."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 12,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-1. It is apparent from the figure that the",
                    "options": [
                        "good is inferior.",
                        "demand for the good decreases as income increases.",
                        "demand for the good conforms to the law of demand.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "demand for the good conforms to the law of demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 13,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "\"Other things equal, when the price of a good rises, the quantity demanded of the good falls, and when the price falls, the quantity demanded rises.\" This relationship between price and quantity demanded",
                    "options": [
                        "applies to most goods in the economy.",
                        "is represented by a downward-sloping demand curve.",
                        "is referred to as the law of demand.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 14,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "\"Other things equal, when the price of a good rises, the quantity demanded of the good falls, and when the price falls, the quantity demanded rises.\" This relationship between price and quantity demanded is referred to as",
                    "options": [
                        "equilibrium.",
                        "the law of demand.",
                        "the relationship between supply and demand.",
                        "the definition of an inferior good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the law of demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 15,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The law of demand states that, other things equal, when the price of a good",
                    "options": [
                        "falls, the demand for the good rises.",
                        "rises, the quantity demanded of the good rises.",
                        "rises, the demand for the good falls.",
                        "falls, the quantity demanded of the good rises."
                    ],
                    "answer": "falls, the quantity demanded of the good rises.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 16,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The law of demand states that, other things equal, an increase in",
                    "options": [
                        "price causes quantity demanded to increase.",
                        "price causes quantity demanded to decrease.",
                        "quantity demanded causes price to increase.",
                        "quantity demanded causes price to decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "price causes quantity demanded to decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 17,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of these statements best represents the law of demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "When buyers' tastes for a good increase, they purchase more of the good.",
                        "When income levels increase, buyers purchase more of most goods.",
                        "When the price of a good decreases, buyers purchase more of the good.",
                        "When buyers' demands for a good increase, the price of the good increases."
                    ],
                    "answer": "When the price of a good decreases, buyers purchase more of the good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 18,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A downward-sloping demand curve illustrates",
                    "options": [
                        "that demand decreases over time.",
                        "that prices fall over time.",
                        "the relationship between income and quantity demanded.",
                        "the law of demand."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the law of demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 19,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Nemo rents 5 movies per month when the price is $3.00 per rental and 7 movies per month when the price is $2.50 per rental. Nemo's demand demonstrates the law of",
                    "options": [
                        "price.",
                        "supply.",
                        "demand.",
                        "income."
                    ],
                    "answer": "demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 20,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following demonstrates the law of demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "After Jon got a raise at work, he bought more pretzels at $1.50 per pretzel than he did before his raise.",
                        "Melissa buys fewer muffins at $0.75 per muffin than at $1 per muffin, other things equal.",
                        "Dave buys more donuts at $0.25 per donut than at $0.50 per donut, other things equal.",
                        "Kendra buys fewer Snickers at $0.60 per Snickers after the price of Milky Ways falls to $0.50 per Milky Way."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Dave buys more donuts at $0.25 per donut than at $0.50 per donut, other things equal.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 21,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The following table contains a demand schedule for a good. Price Quantity Demanded $10 100 $20 Q1 If the law of demand applies to this good, then Q1 could be",
                    "options": [
                        "0.",
                        "100.",
                        "200.",
                        "400."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 22,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price of apple pies rose to $100 per pie, consumers would purchase fewer pies than if the price were $5 per pie. If the price of ice cream fell to $0.30 per scoop, consumers would purchase more ice cream than if the price were $5 per scoop. These relationships illustrate the",
                    "options": [
                        "law of demand.",
                        "law of supply.",
                        "difference between normal and inferior goods.",
                        "difference between substitute and complement goods."
                    ],
                    "answer": "law of demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 23,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A table that shows the relationship between the price of a good and the quantity demanded of that good is called a",
                    "options": [
                        "price-quantity schedule.",
                        "buyer schedule.",
                        "demand schedule.",
                        "demand curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "demand schedule.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 24,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A demand schedule is a table that shows the relationship between",
                    "options": [
                        "quantity demanded and quantity supplied.",
                        "income and quantity demanded.",
                        "price and quantity demanded.",
                        "price and income."
                    ],
                    "answer": "price and quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 25,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is not held constant in a demand schedule?",
                    "options": [
                        "income",
                        "tastes",
                        "price",
                        "expectations"
                    ],
                    "answer": "price",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 26,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The demand curve for a good is a line that relates",
                    "options": [
                        "price and quantity demanded.",
                        "income and quantity demanded.",
                        "quantity demanded and quantity supplied.",
                        "price and income."
                    ],
                    "answer": "price and quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 27,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The line that relates the price of a good and the quantity demanded of that good is called the demand",
                    "options": [
                        "schedule, and it usually slopes upward.",
                        "schedule, and it usually slopes downward.",
                        "curve, and it usually slopes upward.",
                        "curve, and it usually slopes downward."
                    ],
                    "answer": "curve, and it usually slopes downward.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 28,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When drawing a demand curve,",
                    "options": [
                        "demand is measured along the vertical axis, and price is measured along the horizontal axis.",
                        "quantity demanded is measured along the vertical axis, and price is measured along the horizontal axis.",
                        "price is measured along the vertical axis, and demand is measured along the horizontal axis.",
                        "price is measured along the vertical axis, and quantity demanded is measured along the horizontal axis."
                    ],
                    "answer": "price is measured along the vertical axis, and quantity demanded is measured along the horizontal axis.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 29,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When we move along a given demand curve,",
                    "options": [
                        "only price is held constant.",
                        "income and price are held constant.",
                        "all nonprice determinants of demand are held constant.",
                        "all determinants of quantity demanded are held constant."
                    ],
                    "answer": "all nonprice determinants of demand are held constant.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 30,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Once the demand curve for a product or service is drawn, it",
                    "options": [
                        "remains stable over time.",
                        "can shift either rightward or leftward.",
                        "is possible to move along the curve, but the curve will not shift.",
                        "tends to become steeper over time."
                    ],
                    "answer": "can shift either rightward or leftward.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 31,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If something happens to alter the quantity demanded at any given price, then",
                    "options": [
                        "the demand curve becomes steeper.",
                        "the demand curve becomes flatter.",
                        "the demand curve shifts.",
                        "we move along the demand curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the demand curve shifts.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 32,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When quantity demanded decreases at every possible price, the demand curve has",
                    "options": [
                        "shifted to the left.",
                        "shifted to the right.",
                        "not shifted; rather, we have moved along the demand curve to a new point on the same curve.",
                        "not shifted; rather, the demand curve has become flatter."
                    ],
                    "answer": "shifted to the left.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 33,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When quantity demanded increases at every possible price, the demand curve has",
                    "options": [
                        "shifted to the left.",
                        "shifted to the right.",
                        "not shifted; rather, we have moved along the demand curve to a new point on the same curve.",
                        "not shifted; rather, the demand curve has become steeper."
                    ],
                    "answer": "shifted to the right.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 34,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The market demand curve",
                    "options": [
                        "is found by vertically adding the individual demand curves.",
                        "slopes upward.",
                        "represents the sum of the prices that all the buyers are willing to pay for a given quantity of the good.",
                        "represents the sum of the quantities demanded by all the buyers at each price of the good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "represents the sum of the quantities demanded by all the buyers at each price of the good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 35,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The market demand curve",
                    "options": [
                        "is the sum of all individual demand curves.",
                        "is the demand curve for every product in an industry.",
                        "shows the average quantity demanded by individual demanders at each price.",
                        "is always flatter than an individual demand curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "is the sum of all individual demand curves.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 36,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "To obtain the market demand curve for a product, sum the individual demand curves",
                    "options": [
                        "vertically.",
                        "diagonally.",
                        "horizontally.",
                        "and then average them."
                    ],
                    "answer": "horizontally.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 37,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A market demand curve shows",
                    "options": [
                        "the relationship between price and the number of buyers in a market.",
                        "how quantity demanded changes when the number of sellers changes.",
                        "the sum of all prices that individual buyers are willing and able to pay for each possible quantity of the good.",
                        "how much of a good all buyers are willing and able to buy at each possible price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "how much of a good all buyers are willing and able to buy at each possible price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 38,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A market demand curve shows how the total quantity demanded of a good varies as",
                    "options": [
                        "income varies.",
                        "price varies.",
                        "price of the nearest substitute good varies.",
                        "supply varies."
                    ],
                    "answer": "price varies.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 39,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-1. If the market consists of Michelle, Laura, and Hillary and the price falls by $1, the quantity demanded in the market increases by",
                    "options": [
                        "2 units.",
                        "3 units.",
                        "4 units.",
                        "5 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "5 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 40,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-1. If the market consists of Michelle and Laura only and the price falls by $1, the quantity demanded in the market increases by",
                    "options": [
                        "2 units.",
                        "3 units.",
                        "4 units.",
                        "5 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "3 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 41,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-1. If the market consists of Michelle and Hillary only and the price falls by $1, the quantity demanded in the market increases by",
                    "options": [
                        "2 units.",
                        "3 units.",
                        "4 units.",
                        "5 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "3 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 42,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-1. If the market consists of Laura and Hillary only and the price falls by $1, the quantity demanded in the market increases by",
                    "options": [
                        "2 units.",
                        "3 units.",
                        "4 units.",
                        "5 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "4 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 43,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-1. Which of the following illustrates the market demand curve? Price Price 5 4 4 3 3 2 2 1 1 Demand C Demand A 2 4 6 8 10 12 5 Quantity Price 15 20 25 10 15 20 25 30 35 40 45 Quantity Price 5 10 5 4 4 3 3 2 2 1 1 Demand B 4",
                    "options": [
                        "",
                        "5",
                        "",
                        ""
                    ],
                    "answer": "5",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 44,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-2. If Consumer A and Consumer B are the only consumers in the market, then the market quantity demanded when the price is $6 is",
                    "options": [
                        "4 units.",
                        "6 units.",
                        "8 units.",
                        "12 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "12 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 45,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-2. If Consumer A and Consumer B are the only consumers in the market, then the market quantity demanded when the price is $10 is",
                    "options": [
                        "0 units.",
                        "4 units.",
                        "10 units.",
                        "12 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "4 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 46,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-2. Whose demand does not obey the law of demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "William's",
                        "Fergie's",
                        "Taboo's",
                        "apl.de.ap's"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Taboo's",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 47,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-2. If these are the only four buyers in the market, then the market quantity demanded at a price of $8 is",
                    "options": [
                        "4 units.",
                        "6 units.",
                        "24 units.",
                        "32 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "24 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 48,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-2. If these are the only four buyers in the market, then when the price decreases from $6 to $4, the market quantity demanded",
                    "options": [
                        "increases by 0.75 units.",
                        "increases by 3 units.",
                        "increases by 8 units.",
                        "decreases by 27 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increases by 3 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 49,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-3. If these are the only two consumers in the market, then the market quantity demanded at a price of $15 is",
                    "options": [
                        "0 units.",
                        "10 units.",
                        "15 units.",
                        "25 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 50,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-3. If these are the only two consumers in the market, then the market quantity demanded at a price of $10 is",
                    "options": [
                        "0 units.",
                        "5 units.",
                        "8.33 units.",
                        "25 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "8.33 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 51,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-3. If these are the only two consumers in the market, then the market quantity demanded at a price of $6 is",
                    "options": [
                        "12 units.",
                        "14 units.",
                        "19 units.",
                        "21 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "19 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 52,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose Spencer and Kate are the only two demanders of lemonade. Each month, Spencer buys six glasses of lemonade when the price is $1.00 per glass, and he buys four glasses when the price is $1.50 per glass. Each month, Kate buys four glasses of lemonade when the price is $1.00 per glass, and she buys two glasses when the price is $1.50 per glass. Which of the following points is on the market demand curve?",
                    "options": [
                        "(quantity demanded = 2, price = $1.50)",
                        "(quantity demanded = 4, price = $2.50)",
                        "(quantity demanded = 10, price = $1.00)",
                        "(quantity demanded = 16, price = $2.50)"
                    ],
                    "answer": "(quantity demanded = 10, price = $1.00)",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 53,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose Spencer and Kate are the only two demanders of lemonade. Each month, Spencer buys six glasses of lemonade when the price is $1.00 per glass, and he buys four glasses when the price is $1.50 per glass. Each month, Kate buys four glasses of lemonade when the price is $1.00 per glass, and she buys two glasses when the price is $1.50 per glass. Which of the following points is on the market demand curve? Point Price Quantity A $1.00 4 B $1.00 10 C $1.50 2 D $1.50 6",
                    "options": [
                        "B only",
                        "B and D only",
                        "A and C only",
                        "D only"
                    ],
                    "answer": "B and D only",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 54,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-3. Whose demand does not obey the law of demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "Bert's",
                        "Ernie's",
                        "Grover's",
                        "Oscar's"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Grover's",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 55,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-3. If these are the only four buyers in the market, then the market quantity demanded at a price of $1 is",
                    "options": [
                        "4 units.",
                        "7.75 units.",
                        "14 units.",
                        "31 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "31 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 56,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-3. If these are the only four buyers in the market, then the market quantity demanded at a price of $2 is",
                    "options": [
                        "0 units.",
                        "3.5 units.",
                        "12 units.",
                        "14 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "14 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 57,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-3. If these are the only four buyers in the market, then when the price increases from $1.00 to $1.50, the market quantity demanded",
                    "options": [
                        "decreases by 1.75 units.",
                        "increases by 2 units.",
                        "decreases by 7 units.",
                        "decreases by 24 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decreases by 7 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 58,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-3. For whom is the good a normal good?",
                    "options": [
                        "Bert only",
                        "Grover only",
                        "Bert, Ernie, Grover, and Oscar",
                        "This cannot be determined from the table."
                    ],
                    "answer": "This cannot be determined from the table.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 59,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-4. Which of the following would cause the demand curve to shift from Demand B to Demand C in the market for DVDs in the United States?",
                    "options": [
                        "a decrease in the price of DVDs",
                        "a decrease in the price of DVD players",
                        "a change in consumer preferences toward watching movies in movie theaters rather than at home",
                        "a decrease in the number of people in the United States"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in the price of DVD players",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 60,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-4. Which of the following would cause the demand curve to shift from Demand C to Demand A in the market for DVDs?",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in the price of DVDs",
                        "a decrease in the price of DVD players",
                        "a change in consumer preferences toward watching movies in movie theaters rather than at home",
                        "an expectation by buyers that their incomes will increase in the very near future"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a change in consumer preferences toward watching movies in movie theaters rather than at home",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 61,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-4. Which of the following would cause the demand curve to shift from Demand C to Demand A in the market for tennis balls in the United States?",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in the price of tennis balls",
                        "a decrease in the price of tennis racquets",
                        "an expectation by buyers that their incomes will increase in the very near future",
                        "a decrease in the number of people in the United States under age 70"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in the number of people in the United States under age 70",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 62,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-4. Which of the following would cause the demand curve to shift from Demand A to Demand B in the market for golf balls in the United States?",
                    "options": [
                        "a decrease in the price of golf balls",
                        "an increase in the price of green fees",
                        "an expectation by buyers that their incomes will increase in the very near future",
                        "a change in consumer tastes away from golf and toward tennis"
                    ],
                    "answer": "an expectation by buyers that their incomes will increase in the very near future",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 63,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-4. Which of the following would cause the demand curve to shift from Demand A to Demand B in the market for oranges in the United States?",
                    "options": [
                        "a freeze in Florida",
                        "a technological advance that allows oranges to ripen faster",
                        "a decrease in the price of apples",
                        "an announcement by the FDA that oranges prevent heart disease"
                    ],
                    "answer": "an announcement by the FDA that oranges prevent heart disease",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 64,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-5. Suppose that the federal government is concerned about obesity in the United States. Congress is considering two plans. One would require \"junk food\" producers to include warning labels on all junk food. The other would impose a tax on all products considered to be junk food. If the warning labels are successful, we could illustrate the plan as producing a movement from",
                    "options": [
                        "Point A to Point B in Panel 1.",
                        "Point B to Point A in Panel 1.",
                        "Point A to Point C in Panel 2.",
                        "Point C to Point A in Panel 2."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Point A to Point B in Panel 1.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 65,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-5. Suppose that the federal government is concerned about obesity in the United States. Congress is considering two plans. One would require \"junk food\" producers to include warning labels on all junk food. The other would impose a tax on all products considered to be junk food. We could illustrate the tax as producing a movement from",
                    "options": [
                        "Point A to Point B in Panel 1.",
                        "Point B to Point A in Panel 1.",
                        "Point A to Point C in Panel 2.",
                        "Point C to Point A in Panel 2."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Point A to Point C in Panel 2.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 66,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-6. The shift from D to D' is called",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in demand.",
                        "a decrease in demand.",
                        "a decrease in quantity demanded.",
                        "an increase in quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 67,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-6. If the demand curve shifts from D to D', then",
                    "options": [
                        "firms would be willing to supply less of the good than before at each possible price.",
                        "people are willing to buy less of the good than before at each possible price.",
                        "people's incomes must have decreased.",
                        "the price of the product has increased, causing consumers to buy less of the product."
                    ],
                    "answer": "people are willing to buy less of the good than before at each possible price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 68,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-6. The movement from D to D' could be caused by",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in price.",
                        "a decrease in the price of a complement.",
                        "a technological advance.",
                        "a decrease in the price of a substitute."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in the price of a substitute.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 69,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-6. The movement from D' to D could be caused by",
                    "options": [
                        "a decrease in price.",
                        "a decrease in income, assuming the good is inferior.",
                        "buyers expecting the price of the good to fall in the near future.",
                        "an increase in the price of a complement."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in income, assuming the good is inferior.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 70,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-6. The movement from D' to D in the market for potato chips could be caused by a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "decrease in the price of potato chips.",
                        "decrease in income, assuming that potato chips are a normal good.",
                        "announcement by the FDA that potato chips cause cancer.",
                        "increase in the price of a pretzels."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase in the price of a pretzels.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 71,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An increase in demand is represented by a",
                    "options": [
                        "movement downward and to the right along a demand curve.",
                        "movement upward and to the left along a demand curve.",
                        "rightward shift of a demand curve.",
                        "leftward shift of a demand curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "rightward shift of a demand curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 72,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A decrease in demand is represented by a",
                    "options": [
                        "movement downward and to the right along a demand curve.",
                        "movement upward and to the left along a demand curve.",
                        "rightward shift of a demand curve.",
                        "leftward shift of a demand curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "leftward shift of a demand curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 73,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A leftward shift of a demand curve is called a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in demand.",
                        "decrease in demand.",
                        "decrease in quantity demanded.",
                        "increase in quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 74,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A rightward shift of a demand curve is called a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in demand.",
                        "decrease in demand.",
                        "decrease in quantity demanded.",
                        "increase in quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase in demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 75,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If buyers today become more willing and able than before to purchase larger quantities of Vanilla Coke at each price of Vanilla Coke, then",
                    "options": [
                        "we will observe a movement downward and to the right along the demand curve for Vanilla Coke.",
                        "we will observe a movement upward and to the left along the demand curve for Vanilla Coke.",
                        "the demand curve for Vanilla Coke will shift to the right.",
                        "the demand curve for Vanilla Coke will shift to the left."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the demand curve for Vanilla Coke will shift to the right.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 76,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When the price of hot dogs changes, the demand curve for hot dogs",
                    "options": [
                        "shifts because the price of hot dogs is measured on the vertical axis of the graph.",
                        "shifts because the quantity demanded of hot dogs is measured on the horizontal axis of the graph.",
                        "does not shift because the price of hot dogs is measured on the vertical axis of the graph.",
                        "does not shift because the price of hot dogs is measured on the horizontal axis of the graph."
                    ],
                    "answer": "does not shift because the price of hot dogs is measured on the vertical axis of the graph.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 77,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following changes would not shift the demand curve for a good or service?",
                    "options": [
                        "a change in income",
                        "a change in the price of the good or service",
                        "a change in expectations about the future price of the good or service",
                        "a change in the price of a related good or service"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a change in the price of the good or service",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 78,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following would not shift the demand curve for mp3 players?",
                    "options": [
                        "a decrease in the price of mp3 players",
                        "a fad that makes mp3 players more popular among 12-25 year olds",
                        "an increase in the price of digital music downloads, a complement for mp3 players",
                        "a decrease in the price of satellite radio, a substitute for mp3 players"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in the price of mp3 players",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 79,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following events would cause a movement upward and to the left along the demand curve for olives?",
                    "options": [
                        "The number of people who purchase olives decreases.",
                        "Consumer income decreases, and olives are a normal good.",
                        "The price of pickles decreases, and pickles are a substitute for olives.",
                        "The price of olives rises."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The price of olives rises.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 80,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A movement along the demand curve might be caused by a change in",
                    "options": [
                        "income.",
                        "the prices of substitutes or complements.",
                        "expectations about future prices.",
                        "the price of the good or service that is being demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the price of the good or service that is being demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 81,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Holding the nonprice determinants of demand constant, a change in price would",
                    "options": [
                        "result in either a decrease in demand or an increase in demand.",
                        "result in a movement along a stationary demand curve.",
                        "result in a shift of supply.",
                        "have no effect on the quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "result in a movement along a stationary demand curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 82,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The sum of all the individual demand curves for a product is called",
                    "options": [
                        "income demand.",
                        "equilibrium demand.",
                        "complementary demand.",
                        "market demand."
                    ],
                    "answer": "market demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 83,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is not an expression for the sum of all the individual demand curves for a product?",
                    "options": [
                        "total demand",
                        "market demand",
                        "equilibrium demand",
                        "aggregate demand"
                    ],
                    "answer": "equilibrium demand",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 84,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The demand curve for textbooks shifts",
                    "options": [
                        "only when income changes.",
                        "when a determinant of the demand for textbooks other than the price of textbooks changes.",
                        "when the price of textbooks changes.",
                        "Both b) and c) are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "when a determinant of the demand for textbooks other than the price of textbooks changes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 85,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is not a determinant of the demand for a particular good?",
                    "options": [
                        "the prices of related goods",
                        "income",
                        "tastes",
                        "the prices of the inputs used to produce the good"
                    ],
                    "answer": "the prices of the inputs used to produce the good",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 86,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Each of the following is a determinant of demand except",
                    "options": [
                        "tastes.",
                        "production technology.",
                        "expectations.",
                        "the prices of related goods."
                    ],
                    "answer": "production technology.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 87,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is not a determinant of demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "the price of a resource that is used to produce the good",
                        "the price of a complementary good",
                        "the price of the good next month",
                        "the price of a substitute good"
                    ],
                    "answer": "the price of a resource that is used to produce the good",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 88,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the demand for a good falls when income falls, then the good is called a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "normal good.",
                        "regular good.",
                        "luxury good.",
                        "inferior good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "normal good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 89,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a good is normal, then an increase in income will result in a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in the demand for the good.",
                        "decrease in the demand for the good.",
                        "movement down and to the right along the demand curve for the good.",
                        "movement up and to the left along the demand curve for the good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase in the demand for the good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 90,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If Max experiences a decrease in his income, then we would expect Max's demand for",
                    "options": [
                        "each good he purchases to remain unchanged.",
                        "normal goods to decrease.",
                        "luxury goods to increase.",
                        "inferior goods to decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "normal goods to decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 91,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You lose your job and, as a result, you buy fewer iTunes music downloads. This shows that you consider iTunes music downloads to be a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "luxury good.",
                        "inferior good.",
                        "normal good.",
                        "complementary good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "normal good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 92,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Pizza is a normal good if the demand",
                    "options": [
                        "for pizza rises when income rises.",
                        "for pizza rises when the price of pizza falls.",
                        "curve for pizza slopes upward.",
                        "curve for pizza shifts to the right when the price of burritos rises, assuming pizza and burritos are substitutes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "for pizza rises when income rises.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 93,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that when income rises, the demand curve for doctor's visits shifts to the right. In this case, we know doctor's visits are",
                    "options": [
                        "inferior goods.",
                        "normal goods.",
                        "perfectly competitive goods.",
                        "durable goods."
                    ],
                    "answer": "normal goods.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 94,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following would shift the demand curve for gasoline to the right?",
                    "options": [
                        "a decrease in the price of gasoline",
                        "an increase in consumer income, assuming gasoline is a normal good",
                        "an increase in the price of cars, a complement for gasoline",
                        "a decrease in the expected future price of gasoline"
                    ],
                    "answer": "an increase in consumer income, assuming gasoline is a normal good",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 95,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a decrease in income increases the demand for a good, then the good is a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "substitute good.",
                        "complementary good.",
                        "normal good.",
                        "inferior good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "inferior good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 96,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a increase in income decreases the demand for a good, then the good is a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "substitute good.",
                        "complementary good.",
                        "normal good.",
                        "inferior good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "inferior good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 97,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a good is inferior, then an increase in income will result in",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in the demand for the good.",
                        "a decrease in the demand for the good.",
                        "a movement down and to the right along the demand curve for the good.",
                        "a movement up and to the left along the demand curve for the good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in the demand for the good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 98,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Currently you purchase ten frozen pizza per month. You will graduate from college in December, and you will start a new job in January. You have no plans to purchase frozen pizzas in January. For you, frozen pizzas are a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "substitute good.",
                        "normal good.",
                        "inferior good.",
                        "complementary good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "inferior good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 99,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Soup is an inferior good if the demand",
                    "options": [
                        "for soup falls when the price of a substitute for soup rises.",
                        "for soup rises when the price of soup falls.",
                        "curve for soup slopes upward.",
                        "for soup falls when income rises."
                    ],
                    "answer": "for soup falls when income rises.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 100,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that Amanda receives a pay increase. We would expect",
                    "options": [
                        "to observe Amanda moving down and to the right along her given demand curve.",
                        "Amanda's demand for inferior goods to decrease.",
                        "Amanda's demand for each of two goods that are complements to increase.",
                        "Amanda's demand for normal goods to decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Amanda's demand for inferior goods to decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 101,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If macaroni and cheese is an inferior good, then an increase in",
                    "options": [
                        "the price will cause the demand curve for macaroni and cheese to shift to the left.",
                        "the price will cause the demand curve for macaroni and cheese to shift to the right.",
                        "a consumer's income will cause the demand curve for macaroni and cheese to shift to the left.",
                        "a consumer's income will cause the demand curve for macaroni and cheese to shift to the right."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a consumer's income will cause the demand curve for macaroni and cheese to shift to the left.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 102,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Two goods are substitutes when a decrease in the price of one good",
                    "options": [
                        "decreases the demand for the other good.",
                        "decreases the quantity demanded of the other good.",
                        "increases the demand for the other good.",
                        "increases the quantity demanded of the other good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decreases the demand for the other good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 103,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that a decrease in the price of good X results in fewer units of good Y being demanded. This implies that X and Y are",
                    "options": [
                        "complementary goods.",
                        "normal goods.",
                        "inferior goods.",
                        "substitute goods."
                    ],
                    "answer": "substitute goods.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 104,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Good X and good Y are substitutes. If the price of good Y increases, then the",
                    "options": [
                        "demand for good X will decrease.",
                        "quantity demanded of good X will decrease.",
                        "demand for good X will increase.",
                        "quantity demanded of good X will increase."
                    ],
                    "answer": "demand for good X will increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 105,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A likely example of substitute goods for most people would be",
                    "options": [
                        "peanut butter and jelly.",
                        "tennis balls and tennis rackets.",
                        "televisions and subscriptions to cable television services.",
                        "pencils and pens."
                    ],
                    "answer": "pencils and pens.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 106,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If muffins and bagels are substitutes, a higher price for bagels would result in a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in the demand for bagels.",
                        "decrease in the demand for bagels.",
                        "increase in the demand for muffins.",
                        "decrease in the demand for muffins."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase in the demand for muffins.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 107,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You wear either shorts or sweatpants every day. You notice that sweatpants have gone on sale, so your demand for",
                    "options": [
                        "sweatpants will increase.",
                        "sweatpants will decrease.",
                        "shorts will increase.",
                        "shorts will decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "shorts will decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 108,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If American cheese and cheddar cheese are substitutes, then which of the following would increase the demand for cheddar cheese?",
                    "options": [
                        "a decrease in the price of cheddar cheese",
                        "an increase in the price of American cheese",
                        "a decrease in the price of American cheese",
                        "Both a) and b) are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "an increase in the price of American cheese",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 109,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Two goods are complements when a decrease in the price of one good",
                    "options": [
                        "decreases the quantity demanded of the other good.",
                        "decreases the demand for the other good.",
                        "increases the quantity demanded of the other good.",
                        "increases the demand for the other good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increases the demand for the other good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 110,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If goods A and B are complements, then an increase in the price of good A will result in",
                    "options": [
                        "more of good A being sold.",
                        "more of good B being sold.",
                        "less of good B being sold.",
                        "no difference in the quantity sold of either good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "less of good B being sold.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 111,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A likely example of complementary goods for most people would be",
                    "options": [
                        "butter and margarine.",
                        "lawnmowers and automobiles.",
                        "chips and salsa.",
                        "cola and lemonade."
                    ],
                    "answer": "chips and salsa.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 112,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A higher price for batteries would result in a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in the demand for flashlights.",
                        "decrease in the demand for flashlights.",
                        "increase in the demand for batteries.",
                        "decrease in the demand for batteries."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in the demand for flashlights.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 113,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose you like to make, from scratch, pies filled with banana cream and vanilla pudding. You notice that the price of bananas has increased. As a result, your demand for vanilla pudding would",
                    "options": [
                        "decrease.",
                        "increase.",
                        "be unaffected.",
                        "There is insufficient information given to answer the question."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 114,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Holding all other things constant, a higher price for ski lift tickets would",
                    "options": [
                        "increase the number of skiers.",
                        "increase the price of skis.",
                        "decrease the number of skis sold.",
                        "decrease the demand for other winter recreational activities."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease the number of skis sold.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 115,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When quantity demanded has increased at every price, it might be because",
                    "options": [
                        "the number of buyers in the market has decreased.",
                        "income has increased, and the good is an inferior good.",
                        "the costs incurred by sellers producing the good have decreased.",
                        "the price of a complementary good has decreased."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the price of a complementary good has decreased.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 116,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following might cause the demand curve for an inferior good to shift to the left?",
                    "options": [
                        "a decrease in income",
                        "an increase in the price of a substitute",
                        "an increase in the price of a complement",
                        "None of the above is correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "an increase in the price of a complement",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 117,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If toast and butter are complements, then which of the following would increase the demand for toast?",
                    "options": [
                        "a decrease in the price of toast",
                        "a decrease in the price of butter",
                        "an increase in the price of butter",
                        "Both a) and b) are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in the price of butter",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 118,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When it comes to people's tastes, economists generally believe that",
                    "options": [
                        "tastes are based on forces that are well within the realm of economics.",
                        "tastes are based on historical and psychological forces that are beyond the realm of economics.",
                        "tastes can only be studied through well-constructed, real-life models.",
                        "because tastes do not directly affect demand, there is little need to explain people's tastes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "tastes are based on historical and psychological forces that are beyond the realm of economics.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 119,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Economists normally",
                    "options": [
                        "do not try to explain people's tastes, but they do try to explain what happens when tastes change.",
                        "believe that they must be able to explain people's tastes in order to explain what happens when tastes change.",
                        "do not believe that people's tastes determine demand, so they ignore the subject of tastes.",
                        "incorporate tastes into economic models only to the extent that tastes determine whether pairs of goods are substitutes or complements."
                    ],
                    "answer": "do not try to explain people's tastes, but they do try to explain what happens when tastes change.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 120,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose the American Medical Association announces that men who shave their heads are less likely to die of heart failure. We could expect the current demand for",
                    "options": [
                        "hair gel to increase.",
                        "razors to increase.",
                        "combs to increase.",
                        "shampoo to increase."
                    ],
                    "answer": "razors to increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 121,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose scientists provide evidence that chocolate pudding increases the bad cholesterol levels of those who eat it. We would expect to see",
                    "options": [
                        "no change in the demand for chocolate pudding.",
                        "a decrease in the demand for chocolate pudding.",
                        "an increase in the demand for chocolate pudding.",
                        "a decrease in the supply of chocolate pudding."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in the demand for chocolate pudding.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 122,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A very hot summer in Atlanta will cause",
                    "options": [
                        "the demand curve for lemonade to shift to the left.",
                        "the demand for air conditioners to decrease.",
                        "the demand for jackets to decrease.",
                        "a movement downward and to the right along the demand curve for tank tops."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the demand for jackets to decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 123,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a study by medical researchers finds that eating brown rice causes weight loss while eating white rice causes weight gain, then we likely would see",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in demand for brown rice and a decrease in demand for white rice.",
                        "a decrease in demand for brown rice and an increase in demand for white rice.",
                        "an increase in demand for both brown and white rice.",
                        "no change in demand for either type of rice because weight loss is not a determinant of demand."
                    ],
                    "answer": "an increase in demand for brown rice and a decrease in demand for white rice.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 124,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following events could shift the demand curve for gasoline to the left?",
                    "options": [
                        "The income of gasoline buyers rises, and gasoline is a normal good.",
                        "The income of gasoline buyers falls, and gasoline is an inferior good.",
                        "Public service announcements run on television encourage people to walk or ride bicycles instead of driving cars.",
                        "The price of gasoline rises."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Public service announcements run on television encourage people to walk or ride bicycles instead of driving cars.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 125,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An increase in the number of college scholarships issued by private foundations would",
                    "options": [
                        "increase the supply of education.",
                        "decrease the supply of education.",
                        "increase the demand for education.",
                        "decrease the demand for education."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase the demand for education.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 126,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Today, people changed their expectations about the future. This change",
                    "options": [
                        "can cause a movement along a demand curve.",
                        "can affect future demand but not today's demand.",
                        "can affect today's demand.",
                        "cannot affect either today's demand or future demand."
                    ],
                    "answer": "can affect today's demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 127,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If Miguel expects to earn a higher income next month, he may choose to",
                    "options": [
                        "save more now and spend less of his current income on goods and services.",
                        "save less now and spend more of his current income on goods and services.",
                        "decrease his current demand for goods and services.",
                        "move along his current demand curves for goods and services."
                    ],
                    "answer": "save less now and spend more of his current income on goods and services.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 128,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You love peanut butter. You hear on the news that 50 percent of the peanut crop in the South has been wiped out by drought and that this will cause the price of peanuts to double by the end of the year. As a result, your demand for peanut butter",
                    "options": [
                        "will increase but not until the end of the year.",
                        "increases today.",
                        "decreases as you look for a substitute good.",
                        "shifts left today."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increases today.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 129,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Ford Motor Company announces that next month it will offer $3,000 rebates on new Mustangs. As a result of this information, today's demand curve for Mustangs",
                    "options": [
                        "shifts to the right.",
                        "shifts to the left.",
                        "shifts either to the right or to the left, but we cannot determine the direction of the shift from the given information.",
                        "will not shift; rather, the demand curve for Mustangs will shift to the right next month."
                    ],
                    "answer": "shifts to the left.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 130,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What will happen in the artichoke market now if buyers expect higher artichoke prices in the near future?",
                    "options": [
                        "The demand for artichokes will increase.",
                        "The demand for artichokes will decrease.",
                        "The demand for artichokes will be unaffected.",
                        "The supply of artichokes will increase."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The demand for artichokes will increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 131,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Today's demand curve for gasoline could shift in response to a change in",
                    "options": [
                        "today's price of gasoline.",
                        "the expected future price of gasoline.",
                        "the number of sellers of gasoline.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the expected future price of gasoline.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 132,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the number of buyers in a market decreases, then",
                    "options": [
                        "demand will increase.",
                        "demand will decrease.",
                        "supply will increase.",
                        "supply will decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "demand will decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 133,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following does not affect an individual's demand curve?",
                    "options": [
                        "expectations",
                        "income",
                        "prices of related goods",
                        "the number of buyers"
                    ],
                    "answer": "the number of buyers",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 134,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Warrensburg is a small college town in Missouri. At the end of August each year, the market demand for fast food in Warrensburg",
                    "options": [
                        "increases.",
                        "decreases.",
                        "remains constant, but we observe a movement downward and to the right along the demand curve.",
                        "remains constant, but we observe a movement upward and to the left along the demand curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increases.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 135,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For the general population, a 10 percent increase in the price of cigarettes leads to a",
                    "options": [
                        "1 percent reduction in the quantity demanded of cigarettes.",
                        "4 percent reduction in the quantity demanded of cigarettes.",
                        "10 percent reduction in the quantity demanded of cigarettes.",
                        "12 percent reduction in the quantity demanded of cigarettes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "4 percent reduction in the quantity demanded of cigarettes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 136,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For teenagers, a 10 percent increase in the price of cigarettes leads to a",
                    "options": [
                        "1 percent reduction in the quantity demanded of cigarettes.",
                        "4 percent reduction in the quantity demanded of cigarettes.",
                        "10 percent reduction in the quantity demanded of cigarettes.",
                        "12 percent reduction in the quantity demanded of cigarettes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "12 percent reduction in the quantity demanded of cigarettes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 137,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The belief that tobacco is a \"gateway drug\" is consistent with",
                    "options": [
                        "the idea that tobacco and marijuana are substitutes.",
                        "the idea that an increase in income causes a decrease in the demand for tobacco and an increase in the demand for marijuana.",
                        "the idea that lower cigarette prices are associated with less use of marijuana.",
                        "most of the available evidence."
                    ],
                    "answer": "most of the available evidence.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 138,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Most studies indicate that tobacco and marijuana tend to be",
                    "options": [
                        "substitutes.",
                        "complements.",
                        "unrelated because one good is legal while the other one is illegal.",
                        "inferior goods."
                    ],
                    "answer": "complements.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 139,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Opponents of cigarette taxes often argue that tobacco and marijuana are substitutes so that high cigarette prices",
                    "options": [
                        "encourage marijuana use, and the evidence supports this argument.",
                        "encourage marijuana use, but the evidence does not support this argument.",
                        "discourage marijuana use, and the evidence supports this argument.",
                        "discourage marijuana use, but the evidence does not support this argument."
                    ],
                    "answer": "encourage marijuana use, but the evidence does not support this argument.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 140,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-7. The graphs show the demand for cigarettes. In Panel (a), the arrows are consistent with which of the following events?",
                    "options": [
                        "The price of marijuana, a complement to cigarettes, increased.",
                        "Mandatory health warnings were placed on cigarette packages.",
                        "Several foreign countries banned U.S. cigarettes in their countries.",
                        "A tax was placed on cigarettes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "A tax was placed on cigarettes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 141,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-7. The graphs show the demand for cigarettes. In Panel (a), the arrows are consistent with which of the following events?",
                    "options": [
                        "Tobacco and marijuana are complements, and the price of marijuana decreased.",
                        "Tobacco is a \"gateway drug,\" and the price of marijuana increased.",
                        "The price of cigarettes increased.",
                        "The arrows are consistent with all of these events."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The price of cigarettes increased.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 142,
                    "topic": "Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-7. The graphs show the demand for cigarettes. In Panel (b), the arrows are consistent with which of the following events?",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in the price of cigarettes",
                        "placing a tax on cigarettes",
                        "the prohibition of cigarette advertisements on television",
                        "decreasing the price of marijuana, given that tobacco and marijuana are complements"
                    ],
                    "answer": "the prohibition of cigarette advertisements on television",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        },
        "sector4": {
            "title": "Supply",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The quantity supplied of a good is the amount that",
                    "options": [
                        "buyers are willing and able to purchase.",
                        "sellers are able to produce.",
                        "buyers and sellers agree will be brought to market.",
                        "sellers are willing and able to sell."
                    ],
                    "answer": "sellers are willing and able to sell.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price of a good is low,",
                    "options": [
                        "firms would increase profit by increasing output.",
                        "the quantity supplied of the good could be zero.",
                        "the supply curve for the good will shift to the left.",
                        "firms can and should raise the price of the product."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the quantity supplied of the good could be zero.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A decrease in the price of a good will",
                    "options": [
                        "increase supply.",
                        "decrease supply.",
                        "increase quantity supplied.",
                        "decrease quantity supplied."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease quantity supplied.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An increase in the price of a good will",
                    "options": [
                        "increase supply.",
                        "decrease supply.",
                        "increase quantity supplied.",
                        "decrease quantity supplied."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase quantity supplied.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When the price of a good or service changes,",
                    "options": [
                        "the demand curve shifts in the opposite direction.",
                        "the supply curve shifts in the opposite direction.",
                        "the supply curve shifts in the same direction.",
                        "there is a movement along a given supply curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "there is a movement along a given supply curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A movement along the supply curve might be caused by a change in",
                    "options": [
                        "production technology.",
                        "input prices.",
                        "expectations about future prices.",
                        "the price of the good or service that is being supplied."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the price of the good or service that is being supplied.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Holding the nonprice determinants of supply constant, a change in price would",
                    "options": [
                        "result in either a decrease in supply or an increase in supply.",
                        "result in a movement along a stationary supply curve.",
                        "result in a shift of demand.",
                        "have no effect on the quantity supplied."
                    ],
                    "answer": "result in a movement along a stationary supply curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 8,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An increase in the price of a good would",
                    "options": [
                        "increase the supply of the good.",
                        "increase the amount purchased by buyers.",
                        "give producers an incentive to produce more.",
                        "decrease both the quantity demanded of the good and the quantity supplied of the good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "give producers an incentive to produce more.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 9,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An increase in the price of oranges would lead to",
                    "options": [
                        "an increased supply of oranges.",
                        "a reduction in the prices of inputs used in orange production.",
                        "an increased demand for oranges.",
                        "a movement up and to the right along the supply curve for oranges."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a movement up and to the right along the supply curve for oranges.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 10,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An increase in quantity supplied",
                    "options": [
                        "results in a movement downward and to the left along a fixed supply curve.",
                        "results in a movement upward and to the right along a fixed supply curve.",
                        "shifts the supply curve to the left.",
                        "shifts the supply curve to the right."
                    ],
                    "answer": "results in a movement upward and to the right along a fixed supply curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 11,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A decrease in quantity supplied",
                    "options": [
                        "results in a movement downward and to the left along a fixed supply curve.",
                        "results in a movement upward and to the right along a fixed supply curve.",
                        "shifts the supply curve to the left.",
                        "shifts the supply curve to the right."
                    ],
                    "answer": "results in a movement downward and to the left along a fixed supply curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 12,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-8. The movement from Point A to Point B represents a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "shift in the supply curve.",
                        "decrease in the quantity supplied.",
                        "increase in the quantity supplied.",
                        "Both a) and b) are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in the quantity supplied.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 13,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-8. The movement from Point A to Point B represents a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in the price.",
                        "decrease in the quantity supplied.",
                        "shift in the supply curve.",
                        "Both a) and b) are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in the quantity supplied.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 14,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "\"Other things equal, when the price of a good rises, the quantity supplied of the good also rises, and when the price falls, the quantity supplied falls as well.\" This relationship between price and quantity supplied",
                    "options": [
                        "is referred to as the law of supply.",
                        "applies only to a few goods in the economy.",
                        "is represented by a downward-sloping supply curve.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "is referred to as the law of supply.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 15,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The law of supply states that, other things equal, when the price of a good",
                    "options": [
                        "falls, the supply of the good rises.",
                        "rises, the quantity supplied of the good rises.",
                        "rises, the supply of the good falls.",
                        "falls, the quantity supplied of the good rises."
                    ],
                    "answer": "rises, the quantity supplied of the good rises.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 16,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The law of supply states that, other things equal, an increase in",
                    "options": [
                        "price causes quantity supplied to increase.",
                        "price causes quantity supplied to decrease.",
                        "quantity supplied causes price to increase.",
                        "quantity supplied causes price to decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "price causes quantity supplied to increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 17,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Other things equal, when the price of a good falls, the",
                    "options": [
                        "quantity supplied of the good increases.",
                        "supply decreases.",
                        "quantity supplied of the good decreases.",
                        "demand increases."
                    ],
                    "answer": "quantity supplied of the good decreases.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 18,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of these statements best represents the law of supply?",
                    "options": [
                        "When input prices increase, sellers produce less of the good.",
                        "When production technology improves, sellers produce less of the good.",
                        "When the price of a good decreases, sellers produce less of the good.",
                        "When sellers' supplies of a good increase, the price of the good increases."
                    ],
                    "answer": "When the price of a good decreases, sellers produce less of the good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 19,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A supply curve slopes upward because",
                    "options": [
                        "as more is produced, total cost of production falls.",
                        "an increase in input prices increases supply.",
                        "the quantity supplied of most goods and services increases over time.",
                        "an increase in price gives producers an incentive to supply a larger quantity."
                    ],
                    "answer": "an increase in price gives producers an incentive to supply a larger quantity.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 20,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following demonstrates the law of supply?",
                    "options": [
                        "When leather became more expensive, belt producers decreased their supply of belts.",
                        "When car production technology improved, car producers increased their supply of cars.",
                        "When sweater producers expected sweater prices to rise in the near future, they decreased their current supply of sweaters.",
                        "When ketchup prices rose, ketchup sellers increased their quantity supplied of ketchup."
                    ],
                    "answer": "When ketchup prices rose, ketchup sellers increased their quantity supplied of ketchup.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 21,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The following table contains a supply schedule for a good. Price Quantity Supplied $10 100 $20 Q1 If the law of supply applies to this good, then Q1 could be",
                    "options": [
                        "0.",
                        "50.",
                        "100.",
                        "150."
                    ],
                    "answer": "150.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 22,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A supply schedule is a table that shows the relationship between",
                    "options": [
                        "price and quantity supplied.",
                        "input costs and quantity supplied.",
                        "quantity demanded and quantity supplied.",
                        "profit and quantity supplied."
                    ],
                    "answer": "price and quantity supplied.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 23,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is not held constant in a supply schedule?",
                    "options": [
                        "production technology",
                        "the price of the good",
                        "the prices of inputs",
                        "expectations"
                    ],
                    "answer": "the price of the good",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 24,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The difference between a supply schedule and a supply curve is that a supply schedule",
                    "options": [
                        "incorporates demand and a supply curve does not.",
                        "incorporates profit and a supply curve does not.",
                        "can shift, but a supply curve cannot shift.",
                        "is a table, and a supply curve is drawn on a graph."
                    ],
                    "answer": "is a table, and a supply curve is drawn on a graph.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 25,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-9. The movement from point A to point B on the graph is called",
                    "options": [
                        "a decrease in supply.",
                        "an increase in supply.",
                        "an increase in the quantity supplied.",
                        "a decrease in the quantity supplied."
                    ],
                    "answer": "an increase in the quantity supplied.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 26,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-9. The movement from point A to point B on the graph is caused by",
                    "options": [
                        "a decrease in the price of the good.",
                        "an increase in the price of the good.",
                        "an advance in production technology.",
                        "a decrease in input prices."
                    ],
                    "answer": "an increase in the price of the good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 27,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-9. The movement from point A to point B on the graph represents",
                    "options": [
                        "an increased willingness and ability on the part of suppliers to supply the good at each possible price.",
                        "an increase in the number of suppliers.",
                        "a decrease in the price of a relevant input.",
                        "an increase in the price of the good that is being supplied and the suppliers' responses to that price change."
                    ],
                    "answer": "an increase in the price of the good that is being supplied and the suppliers' responses to that price change.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 28,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-10. Which of the following would cause the supply curve to shift from Supply A to Supply C in the market for tennis racquets?",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in the price of tennis balls",
                        "an expectation by firms that the price of tennis racquets will increase in the very near future",
                        "a decrease in the price of tennis racquet strings",
                        "a decrease in the number of firms selling tennis racquets"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in the price of tennis racquet strings",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 29,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-10. Which of the following would cause the supply curve to shift from Supply A to Supply C in the market for winter coats?",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in the price of winter coats",
                        "a decrease in the number of firms selling winter coats",
                        "a decrease in the price of zippers and snaps",
                        "a decrease in the price of winter hats and gloves"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in the price of zippers and snaps",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 30,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-10. Which of the following would cause the supply curve to shift from Supply B to Supply A in the market for tennis racquets?",
                    "options": [
                        "a decrease in the price of tennis balls",
                        "an expectation by firms that the price of tennis racquets will increase in the very near future",
                        "a decrease in the price of tennis racquet strings",
                        "an improvement in technology that allows firms to use less labor in the production of tennis racquets"
                    ],
                    "answer": "an expectation by firms that the price of tennis racquets will increase in the very near future",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 31,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-10. Which of the following would cause the supply curve to shift from Supply B to Supply A in the market for disposable ballpoint pens?",
                    "options": [
                        "a decrease in the price of disposable ballpoint pens",
                        "an increase in the price of fountain pens",
                        "an increase in the price of ink",
                        "an improvement in technology that allows firms to use less labor in the production of disposable ballpoint pens"
                    ],
                    "answer": "an increase in the price of ink",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 32,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The supply curve for a good is a line that relates",
                    "options": [
                        "profit and quantity supplied.",
                        "quantity supplied and quantity demanded.",
                        "price and quantity supplied.",
                        "price and profit."
                    ],
                    "answer": "price and quantity supplied.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 33,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The line that relates the price of a good and the quantity supplied of that good is called the supply",
                    "options": [
                        "schedule, and it usually slopes upward.",
                        "schedule, and it usually slopes downward.",
                        "curve, and it usually slopes upward.",
                        "curve, and it usually slopes downward."
                    ],
                    "answer": "curve, and it usually slopes upward.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 34,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When we move along a given supply curve,",
                    "options": [
                        "only price is held constant.",
                        "technology and price are held constant.",
                        "all nonprice determinants of supply are held constant.",
                        "all determinants of quantity supplied are held constant."
                    ],
                    "answer": "all nonprice determinants of supply are held constant.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 35,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Once the supply curve for a product or service is drawn, it",
                    "options": [
                        "remains stable over time.",
                        "can shift either rightward or leftward.",
                        "is possible to move along the curve, but the curve will not shift.",
                        "tends to become steeper over time."
                    ],
                    "answer": "can shift either rightward or leftward.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 36,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If something happens to alter the quantity supplied at any given price, then",
                    "options": [
                        "we move along the supply curve.",
                        "the supply curve shifts.",
                        "the supply curve becomes steeper.",
                        "the supply curve becomes flatter."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the supply curve shifts.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 37,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An increase in supply is represented by a",
                    "options": [
                        "movement downward and to the left along a supply curve.",
                        "movement upward and to the right along a supply curve.",
                        "rightward shift of a supply curve.",
                        "leftward shift of a supply curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "rightward shift of a supply curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 38,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A decrease in supply is represented by a",
                    "options": [
                        "movement downward and to the left along a supply curve.",
                        "movement upward and to the right along a supply curve.",
                        "rightward shift of a supply curve.",
                        "leftward shift of a supply curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "leftward shift of a supply curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 39,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A leftward shift of a supply curve is called a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in supply.",
                        "decrease in supply.",
                        "decrease in quantity supplied.",
                        "increase in quantity supplied."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in supply.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 40,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A rightward shift of a supply curve is called a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in supply.",
                        "decrease in supply.",
                        "decrease in quantity supplied.",
                        "increase in quantity supplied."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase in supply.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 41,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A movement upward and to the right along a supply curve is called a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in supply.",
                        "decrease in supply.",
                        "decrease in quantity supplied.",
                        "increase in quantity supplied."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase in quantity supplied.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 42,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A movement downward and to the left along a supply curve is called a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in supply.",
                        "decrease in supply.",
                        "decrease in quantity supplied.",
                        "increase in quantity supplied."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in quantity supplied.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 43,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When quantity supplied decreases at every possible price, we know that the supply curve has",
                    "options": [
                        "shifted to the left.",
                        "shifted to the right.",
                        "not shifted; rather, we have moved along the supply curve to a new point on the same curve.",
                        "not shifted; rather, the supply curve has become flatter."
                    ],
                    "answer": "shifted to the left.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 44,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When quantity supplied increases at every possible price, we know that the supply curve has",
                    "options": [
                        "shifted to the left.",
                        "shifted to the right.",
                        "not shifted; rather, we have moved along the supply curve to a new point on the same curve.",
                        "not shifted; rather, the supply curve has become flatter."
                    ],
                    "answer": "shifted to the right.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 45,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The supply curve for milk",
                    "options": [
                        "shifts when the price of milk changes because the price of milk is measured on the vertical axis of the graph.",
                        "shifts when the price of milk changes because the quantity supplied of milk is measured on the horizontal axis of the graph.",
                        "does not shift when the price of milk changes because the price of milk is measured on the vertical axis of the graph.",
                        "does not shift when the price of milk changes because the price of milk is measured on the horizontal axis of the graph."
                    ],
                    "answer": "does not shift when the price of milk changes because the price of milk is measured on the vertical axis of the graph.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 46,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following changes would not shift the supply curve for a good or service?",
                    "options": [
                        "a change in production technology",
                        "a change in the price of the good or service",
                        "a change in expectations about the future price of the good or service",
                        "a change in input prices"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a change in the price of the good or service",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 47,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following would not shift the supply curve for mp3 players?",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in the price of mp3 players",
                        "a decrease in the number of sellers of mp3 players",
                        "an increase in the price of plastic, an input into the production of mp3 players",
                        "an improvement in the technology used to produce mp3 players"
                    ],
                    "answer": "an increase in the price of mp3 players",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 48,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following events would cause a movement upward and to the right along the supply curve for mangos?",
                    "options": [
                        "The number of sellers of mangos increases.",
                        "There is an advance in technology that reduces the cost of producing mangos.",
                        "The price of fertilizer decreases, and fertilizer is an input in the production of mangos.",
                        "The price of mangos rises."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The price of mangos rises.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 49,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The sum of all the individual supply curves for a product is called",
                    "options": [
                        "total supply.",
                        "market supply.",
                        "aggregate supply.",
                        "total output."
                    ],
                    "answer": "market supply.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 50,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The market supply curve",
                    "options": [
                        "is found by vertically adding the individual supply curves.",
                        "slopes downward.",
                        "represents the sum of the prices that all the sellers are willing to accept for a given quantity of the good.",
                        "represents the sum of the quantities supplied by all the sellers at each price of the good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "represents the sum of the quantities supplied by all the sellers at each price of the good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 51,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In a market, to find the total amount supplied at a particular price, we must",
                    "options": [
                        "sum the quantities that individual firms are willing and able to supply at that price.",
                        "calculate the average of the quantities that individual firms are willing and able to supply at that price.",
                        "sum the costs that individual firms incur to supply the product at that price.",
                        "account for all determinants of demand."
                    ],
                    "answer": "sum the quantities that individual firms are willing and able to supply at that price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 52,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A market supply curve is determined by",
                    "options": [
                        "vertically summing individual supply curves.",
                        "horizontally summing individual supply curves.",
                        "finding the average quantity supplied by sellers at each possible price.",
                        "finding the average price at which sellers are willing and able to sell a particular quantity of the good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "horizontally summing individual supply curves.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 53,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A market supply curve shows",
                    "options": [
                        "the total quantity supplied at all possible prices.",
                        "the average quantity supplied by producers at all possible prices.",
                        "how quantity supplied changes when consumer income changes.",
                        "suppliers' responses, in terms of the amounts they will supply, to the demands of buyers."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the total quantity supplied at all possible prices.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 54,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A market supply curve shows how the total quantity supplied of a good varies as",
                    "options": [
                        "production technology varies.",
                        "price varies.",
                        "input prices vary.",
                        "demand varies."
                    ],
                    "answer": "price varies.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 55,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose there are five suppliers of ice cream in the town of Summerville. If we add the respective quantities that each firm would produce at each of the five ice cream parlors when the price of ice cream is $2 per scoop, $2.50 per scoop, and $3 per scoop, and so forth, we have found the",
                    "options": [
                        "market demand curve.",
                        "market supply curve.",
                        "equilibrium curve.",
                        "surplus or shortage depending on market conditions."
                    ],
                    "answer": "market supply curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 56,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-4. Which supply schedules obey the law of supply?",
                    "options": [
                        "Firm A's only",
                        "Firm B's, Firm C's, and Firm D's only",
                        "Firm A's and Firm C's only",
                        "Firm B's and Firm D's only"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Firm B's and Firm D's only",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 57,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-4. If these are the only four sellers in the market, then the market quantity supplied at a price of $4 is",
                    "options": [
                        "4 units.",
                        "7.5 units.",
                        "10 units.",
                        "30 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "30 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 58,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-4. If these are the only four sellers in the market, then the market quantity supplied at a price of $10 is",
                    "options": [
                        "3 units.",
                        "11 units.",
                        "25 units.",
                        "44 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "44 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 59,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-4. If these are the only four sellers in the market, then when the price increases from $6 to $8, the market quantity supplied",
                    "options": [
                        "increases by 0.5 units.",
                        "increases by 2 units.",
                        "decreases by 4 units.",
                        "increases by 42 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increases by 2 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 60,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-4. If these are the only four sellers in the market, then when the price decreases from $4 to $2, the market quantity supplied",
                    "options": [
                        "increases by 10 units.",
                        "decreases by 10 units.",
                        "decreases by 20 units.",
                        "decreases by 30 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decreases by 10 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 61,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-5. If these are the only four sellers in the market, then the market quantity supplied at a price of $4 is",
                    "options": [
                        "4 units.",
                        "5 units.",
                        "20 units.",
                        "80 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "20 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 62,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-5. If these are the only four sellers in the market, then the market quantity supplied at a price of $8 is",
                    "options": [
                        "10 units.",
                        "20 units.",
                        "32 units.",
                        "40 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "40 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 63,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-5. If these are the only four sellers in the market, then when the price decreases from $10 to $8, the market quantity supplied decreases by",
                    "options": [
                        "2.5 units.",
                        "4 units.",
                        "10 units.",
                        "50 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "10 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 64,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-5. If these are the only four sellers in the market, then when the price increases from $4 to $6, the market quantity supplied",
                    "options": [
                        "decreases by 10 units.",
                        "decreases by 20 units.",
                        "increases by 10 units.",
                        "increases by 20 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increases by 10 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 65,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-11. If these are the only two sellers in the market, then the market quantity supplied at a price of $4 is",
                    "options": [
                        "6 units.",
                        "7 units.",
                        "8 units.",
                        "14 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "14 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 66,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-11. If these are the only two sellers in the market, then the market quantity supplied at a price of $6 is",
                    "options": [
                        "2 units.",
                        "10 units.",
                        "12 units.",
                        "22 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "22 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 67,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-11. If these are the only two sellers in the market, then the market quantity supplied at a price of $8 is",
                    "options": [
                        "14 units.",
                        "15 units.",
                        "16 units.",
                        "29 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "29 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 68,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-12. If Producer A and Producer B are the only producers in the market, then the market quantity supplied when the price is $4 is",
                    "options": [
                        "4 units.",
                        "8 units.",
                        "12 units.",
                        "16 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "12 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 69,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The supply curve for portable charcoal grills shifts",
                    "options": [
                        "only when production technology changes.",
                        "when a determinant of the supply of portable charcoal grills other than the price of portable charcoal grills changes.",
                        "when any determinant of the supply of portable charcoal grills changes.",
                        "only when the number of sellers of portable charcoal grills changes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "when a determinant of the supply of portable charcoal grills other than the price of portable charcoal grills changes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 70,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Lead is an important input in the production of crystal. If the price of lead decreases, then we would expect the supply of",
                    "options": [
                        "crystal to be unaffected.",
                        "crystal to decrease.",
                        "crystal to increase.",
                        "lead to increase."
                    ],
                    "answer": "crystal to increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 71,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose you make jewelry. If the price of gold falls, then we would expect you to",
                    "options": [
                        "be willing and able to produce less jewelry than before at each possible price.",
                        "be willing and able to produce more jewelry than before at each possible price.",
                        "face a greater demand for your jewelry.",
                        "face a weaker demand for your jewelry."
                    ],
                    "answer": "be willing and able to produce more jewelry than before at each possible price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 72,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Workers at a bicycle assembly plant currently earn the mandatory minimum wage. If the federal government increases the minimum wage by $1.00 per hour, then it is likely that the",
                    "options": [
                        "demand for bicycle assembly workers will increase.",
                        "supply of bicycles will shift to the right.",
                        "supply of bicycles will shift to the left.",
                        "firm must increase output to maintain profit levels."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply of bicycles will shift to the left.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 73,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose there is an increase in the price of steel. We would expect the supply curve for steel beams to",
                    "options": [
                        "shift rightward.",
                        "shift leftward.",
                        "become flatter.",
                        "remain unchanged."
                    ],
                    "answer": "shift leftward.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 74,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Wheat is the main input in the production of flour. If the price of wheat decreases, then we would expect the",
                    "options": [
                        "demand for flour to increase.",
                        "demand for flour to decrease.",
                        "supply of flour to increase.",
                        "supply of flour to decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply of flour to increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 75,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Matthew bakes apple pies that he sells at the local farmer's market. If the price of apples increases, the",
                    "options": [
                        "supply curve for Matthew's pies will increase.",
                        "supply curve for Matthew's pies will decrease.",
                        "demand curve for Matthew's pies will increase.",
                        "demand curve for Matthew's pies will decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply curve for Matthew's pies will decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 76,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose an increase in the price of rubber coincides with an advance in the technology of tire production. As a result of these two events, the demand for tires",
                    "options": [
                        "decreases, and the supply of tires increases.",
                        "is unaffected, and the supply of tires decreases.",
                        "is unaffected, and the supply of tires increases.",
                        "None of the above is necessarily correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "None of the above is necessarily correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 77,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A improvement in production technology will shift the",
                    "options": [
                        "supply curve to the right.",
                        "supply curve to the left.",
                        "demand curve to the right.",
                        "demand curve to the left."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply curve to the right.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 78,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An improvement in production technology will",
                    "options": [
                        "increase a firm's costs and increase its supply.",
                        "increase a firm's costs and decrease its supply.",
                        "decrease a firm's costs and increase its supply.",
                        "decrease a firm's costs and decrease its supply."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease a firm's costs and increase its supply.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 79,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If car manufacturers begin using new labor-saving technology on their assembly lines, we would not expect",
                    "options": [
                        "a smaller quantity of labor to be used.",
                        "the supply of cars to increase.",
                        "the firms' costs to fall.",
                        "individual car manufacturers to move up and to the right along their individual supply curves."
                    ],
                    "answer": "individual car manufacturers to move up and to the right along their individual supply curves.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 80,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following might cause the supply curve for an inferior good to shift to the right?",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in input prices",
                        "a decrease in consumer income",
                        "an improvement in production technology that makes production of the good more profitable",
                        "a decrease in the number of sellers in the market"
                    ],
                    "answer": "an improvement in production technology that makes production of the good more profitable",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 81,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Ashley bakes bread that she sells at the local farmer's market. If she purchases a new convection oven that reduces the costs of baking bread, the",
                    "options": [
                        "supply curve for Ashley's bread will increase.",
                        "supply curve for Ashley's bread will decrease.",
                        "demand curve for Ashley's bread will increase.",
                        "demand curve for Ashley's bread will decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply curve for Ashley's bread will increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 82,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Today, producers changed their expectations about the future. This change",
                    "options": [
                        "can cause a movement along a supply curve.",
                        "can affect future supply, but not today's supply.",
                        "can affect today's supply.",
                        "cannot affect either today's supply or future supply."
                    ],
                    "answer": "can affect today's supply.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 83,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If suppliers expect the price of their product to fall in the future, then they will",
                    "options": [
                        "decrease supply now.",
                        "increase supply now.",
                        "decrease supply in the future but not now.",
                        "increase supply in the future but not now."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase supply now.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 84,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If sellers expect higher basket prices in the near future, the current",
                    "options": [
                        "supply of baskets will increase.",
                        "supply of baskets will decrease.",
                        "supply of baskets will be unaffected.",
                        "demand for baskets will decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply of baskets will decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 85,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Today's supply curve for gasoline could shift in response to a change in",
                    "options": [
                        "today's price of gasoline.",
                        "the expected future price of gasoline.",
                        "the number of buyers of gasoline.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the expected future price of gasoline.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 86,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A dress manufacturer recently has come to expect higher prices for dresses in the near future. We would expect",
                    "options": [
                        "the dress manufacturer to supply more dresses now than it was supplying previously.",
                        "the dress manufacturer to supply fewer dresses now than it was supplying previously.",
                        "the demand for this manufacturer's dresses to fall.",
                        "no change in the dress manufacturer's current supply; instead, future supply will be affected."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the dress manufacturer to supply fewer dresses now than it was supplying previously.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 87,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Recent forest fires in the western states are expected to cause the price of lumber to rise in the next six months. As a result, we can expect the supply of lumber to",
                    "options": [
                        "fall in six months but not now.",
                        "increase in six months when the price goes up.",
                        "fall now.",
                        "increase now to meet as much demand as possible."
                    ],
                    "answer": "fall now.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 88,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Funsters, Inc., the largest toy company in the country, sells its most popular doll for $15. It has just learned that its leading competitor, Toysorama, is mass-producing an excellent copy and plans to flood the market with their $5 doll in six weeks. Funsters should",
                    "options": [
                        "\"fight fire with fire\" by decreasing supply of its doll for six weeks and then increasing the supply.",
                        "increase the supply of its doll now before the other doll hits the market.",
                        "increase the price of its doll now.",
                        "discontinue its doll."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase the supply of its doll now before the other doll hits the market.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 89,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is a determinant of the market supply curve but not a determinant of an individual seller's supply?",
                    "options": [
                        "production technology",
                        "expectations",
                        "input prices",
                        "the number of sellers"
                    ],
                    "answer": "the number of sellers",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 90,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the number of sellers in a market increases, then the",
                    "options": [
                        "demand in that market will increase.",
                        "supply in that market will increase.",
                        "supply in that market will decrease.",
                        "demand in that market will decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply in that market will increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 91,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A decrease in the number of sellers in the market causes",
                    "options": [
                        "the supply curve to shift to the left.",
                        "the supply curve to shift to the right.",
                        "a movement up and to the right along a stationary supply curve.",
                        "a movement downward and to the left along a stationary supply curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the supply curve to shift to the left.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 92,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An increase in which of the following would shift the supply curve for gasoline to the right?",
                    "options": [
                        "demand for gasoline",
                        "price of gasoline",
                        "number of producers of gasoline",
                        "price of oil, an input into the production of gasoline"
                    ],
                    "answer": "number of producers of gasoline",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 93,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following events could cause an increase in the supply of ceiling fans?",
                    "options": [
                        "The number of sellers of ceiling fans increases.",
                        "There is an increase in the price of air conditioners, and consumers regard air conditioners and ceiling fans as substitutes.",
                        "There is an increase in the price of the motor that powers ceiling fans.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The number of sellers of ceiling fans increases.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 94,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-13. The shift from S to S' is called a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "decrease in supply.",
                        "decrease in quantity supplied.",
                        "increase in supply.",
                        "increase in quantity supplied."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase in supply.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 95,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-13. The shift from S to S' could be caused by an",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in the price of the good.",
                        "improvement in production technology.",
                        "increase in income.",
                        "increase in input prices."
                    ],
                    "answer": "improvement in production technology.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 96,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-13. The shift from S to S' in the market for peaches could be caused by a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in the price of peaches.",
                        "decrease in the price of pears.",
                        "increase in income.",
                        "decrease in the labor costs of the workers who pick peaches."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in the labor costs of the workers who pick peaches.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 97,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-13. The shift from S' to S in the market for chocolate cake could be caused by a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "decrease in the number of commercial bakers.",
                        "improvement in oven technology.",
                        "decrease in the price of butter.",
                        "decrease in the price of chocolate cake."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in the number of commercial bakers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 98,
                    "topic": "Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-13. If the supply curves that are drawn represent supply curves for single-family residential houses, then the movement from S to S' could be caused by a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in the price of apartments which are a substitute for single-family houses for many people looking for a place to live.",
                        "newly-formed expectation by house-builders that prices of houses will increase significantly in the next six months.",
                        "decrease in the price of lumber.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in the price of lumber.",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        },
        "sector5": {
            "title": "Supply And Demand Together",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The unique point at which the supply and demand curves intersect is called",
                    "options": [
                        "market harmony.",
                        "coincidence.",
                        "equivalence.",
                        "equilibrium."
                    ],
                    "answer": "equilibrium.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The dictionary defines equilibrium as a situation in which forces",
                    "options": [
                        "are in balance.",
                        "are the same.",
                        "clash.",
                        "remain constant."
                    ],
                    "answer": "are in balance.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "At the equilibrium price, the quantity of the good that buyers are willing and able to buy",
                    "options": [
                        "is greater than the quantity that sellers are willing and able to sell.",
                        "exactly equals the quantity that sellers are willing and able to sell.",
                        "is less than the quantity that sellers are willing and able to sell.",
                        "Either a) or c) could be correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "exactly equals the quantity that sellers are willing and able to sell.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Another term for equilibrium price is",
                    "options": [
                        "dynamic price.",
                        "market-clearing price.",
                        "quantity-defining price.",
                        "balance price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "market-clearing price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In a given market, how are the equilibrium price and the market-clearing price related?",
                    "options": [
                        "There is no relationship.",
                        "They are the same price.",
                        "The market-clearing price exceeds the equilibrium price.",
                        "The equilibrium price exceeds the market-clearing price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "They are the same price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Buyers are able to buy all they want to buy and sellers are able to sell all they want to sell at",
                    "options": [
                        "prices at and above the equilibrium price.",
                        "prices at and below the equilibrium price.",
                        "prices above and below the equilibrium price, but not at the equilibrium price.",
                        "the equilibrium price but not above or below the equilibrium price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the equilibrium price but not above or below the equilibrium price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In markets, prices move toward equilibrium because of",
                    "options": [
                        "the actions of buyers and sellers.",
                        "government regulations placed on market participants.",
                        "increased competition among sellers.",
                        "buyers' ability to affect market outcomes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the actions of buyers and sellers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 8,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following events must cause equilibrium quantity to fall?",
                    "options": [
                        "demand increases and supply decreases",
                        "demand and supply both decrease",
                        "demand decreases and supply increases",
                        "demand and supply both increase"
                    ],
                    "answer": "demand and supply both decrease",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 9,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following events must cause equilibrium quantity to rise?",
                    "options": [
                        "demand increases and supply decreases",
                        "demand and supply both decrease",
                        "demand decreases and supply increases",
                        "demand and supply both increase"
                    ],
                    "answer": "demand and supply both increase",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 10,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following events must cause equilibrium price to fall?",
                    "options": [
                        "demand increases and supply decreases",
                        "demand and supply both decrease",
                        "demand decreases and supply increases",
                        "demand and supply both increase"
                    ],
                    "answer": "demand decreases and supply increases",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 11,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Equilibrium quantity must decrease when demand",
                    "options": [
                        "increases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply decreases, and when both demand and supply decrease.",
                        "increases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply increases, and when both demand and supply decrease.",
                        "decreases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply increases, and when both demand and supply decrease.",
                        "decreases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply decreases, and when both demand and supply decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decreases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply decreases, and when both demand and supply decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 12,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Equilibrium quantity must increase when demand",
                    "options": [
                        "increases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply increases, and when both demand and supply increase.",
                        "increases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply increases, and when both demand and supply decrease.",
                        "decreases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply decreases, and when both demand and supply increase.",
                        "decreases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply decreases, and when both demand and supply decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply increases, and when both demand and supply increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 13,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Equilibrium price must decrease when demand",
                    "options": [
                        "increases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply decreases, and when demand decreases and supply increases simultaneously.",
                        "increases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply decreases, and when demand increases and supply decreases simultaneously.",
                        "decreases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply increases, and when demand decreases and supply increases simultaneously.",
                        "decreases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply increases, and when demand increases and supply decreases simultaneously."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decreases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply increases, and when demand decreases and supply increases simultaneously.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 14,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Equilibrium price must increase when demand",
                    "options": [
                        "increases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply decreases, and when demand decreases and supply increases simultaneously.",
                        "increases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply decreases, and when demand increases and supply decreases simultaneously.",
                        "decreases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply increases, and when demand decreases and supply increases simultaneously.",
                        "decreases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply increases, and when demand increases and supply decreases simultaneously."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increases and supply does not change, when demand does not change and supply decreases, and when demand increases and supply decreases simultaneously.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 15,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following events must cause equilibrium price to rise?",
                    "options": [
                        "demand increases and supply decreases",
                        "demand and supply both decrease",
                        "demand decreases and supply increases",
                        "demand and supply both increase"
                    ],
                    "answer": "demand increases and supply decreases",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 16,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the demand for a product increases, then we would expect equilibrium price",
                    "options": [
                        "to increase and equilibrium quantity to decrease.",
                        "to decrease and equilibrium quantity to increase.",
                        "and equilibrium quantity both to increase.",
                        "and equilibrium quantity both to decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "and equilibrium quantity both to increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 17,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the demand for a product decreases, then we would expect equilibrium price",
                    "options": [
                        "to increase and equilibrium quantity to decrease.",
                        "to decrease and equilibrium quantity to increase.",
                        "and equilibrium quantity to both increase.",
                        "and equilibrium quantity to both decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "and equilibrium quantity to both decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 18,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the supply of a product increases, then we would expect equilibrium price",
                    "options": [
                        "to increase and equilibrium quantity to decrease.",
                        "to decrease and equilibrium quantity to increase.",
                        "and equilibrium quantity to both increase.",
                        "and equilibrium quantity to both decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "to decrease and equilibrium quantity to increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 19,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the supply of a product decreases, then we would expect equilibrium price",
                    "options": [
                        "to increase and equilibrium quantity to decrease.",
                        "to decrease and equilibrium quantity to increase.",
                        "and equilibrium quantity to both increase.",
                        "and equilibrium quantity to both decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "to increase and equilibrium quantity to decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 20,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When supply and demand both increase, equilibrium",
                    "options": [
                        "price will increase.",
                        "price will decrease.",
                        "quantity may increase, decrease, or remain unchanged.",
                        "price may increase, decrease, or remain unchanged."
                    ],
                    "answer": "price may increase, decrease, or remain unchanged.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 21,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that demand for a good increases and, at the same time, supply of the good decreases. What would happen in the market for the good?",
                    "options": [
                        "Equilibrium price would decrease, but the impact on equilibrium quantity would be ambiguous.",
                        "Equilibrium price would increase, but the impact on equilibrium quantity would be ambiguous.",
                        "Equilibrium quantity would decrease, but the impact on equilibrium price would be ambiguous.",
                        "Equilibrium quantity would increase, but the impact on equilibrium price would be ambiguous."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Equilibrium price would increase, but the impact on equilibrium quantity would be ambiguous.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 22,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that demand for a good decreases and, at the same time, supply of the good decreases. What would happen in the market for the good?",
                    "options": [
                        "Equilibrium price would decrease, but the impact on equilibrium quantity would be ambiguous.",
                        "Equilibrium price would increase, but the impact on equilibrium quantity would be ambiguous.",
                        "Equilibrium quantity would decrease, but the impact on equilibrium price would be ambiguous.",
                        "Equilibrium quantity would increase, but the impact on equilibrium price would be ambiguous."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Equilibrium quantity would decrease, but the impact on equilibrium price would be ambiguous.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 23,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-6. Which combination would produce an increase in equilibrium quantity and an indeterminate change in equilibrium price?",
                    "options": [
                        "A",
                        "B",
                        "C",
                        "D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "A",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 24,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-6. Which combination would produce an increase in equilibrium price and an indeterminate change in equilibrium quantity?",
                    "options": [
                        "A",
                        "B",
                        "C",
                        "D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "B",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 25,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-6. Which combination would produce a decrease in equilibrium price and an indeterminate change in equilibrium quantity?",
                    "options": [
                        "A",
                        "B",
                        "C",
                        "D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "C",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 26,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-6. Which combination would produce a decrease in equilibrium quantity and an indeterminate change in equilibrium price?",
                    "options": [
                        "A",
                        "B",
                        "C",
                        "D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "D",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 27,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following would cause price to decrease?",
                    "options": [
                        "a decrease in supply",
                        "an increase in demand",
                        "a surplus of the good",
                        "a shortage of the good"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a surplus of the good",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 28,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When the price of a good is higher than the equilibrium price,",
                    "options": [
                        "a shortage will exist.",
                        "buyers desire to purchase more than is produced.",
                        "sellers desire to produce and sell more than buyers wish to purchase.",
                        "quantity demanded exceeds quantity supplied."
                    ],
                    "answer": "sellers desire to produce and sell more than buyers wish to purchase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 29,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A surplus exists in a market if",
                    "options": [
                        "there is an excess demand for the good.",
                        "quantity demanded exceeds quantity supplied.",
                        "the current price is above its equilibrium price.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the current price is above its equilibrium price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 30,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a surplus exists in a market, then we know that the actual price is",
                    "options": [
                        "above the equilibrium price, and quantity supplied is greater than quantity demanded.",
                        "above the equilibrium price, and quantity demanded is greater than quantity supplied.",
                        "below the equilibrium price, and quantity demanded is greater than quantity supplied.",
                        "below the equilibrium price, and quantity supplied is greater than quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "above the equilibrium price, and quantity supplied is greater than quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 31,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If, at the current price, there is a surplus of a good, then",
                    "options": [
                        "sellers are producing more than buyers wish to buy.",
                        "the market must be in equilibrium.",
                        "the price is below the equilibrium price.",
                        "quantity demanded equals quantity supplied."
                    ],
                    "answer": "sellers are producing more than buyers wish to buy.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 32,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When a surplus exists in a market, sellers",
                    "options": [
                        "raise price, which increases quantity demanded and decreases quantity supplied, until the surplus is eliminated.",
                        "raise price, which decreases quantity demanded and increases quantity supplied, until the surplus is eliminated.",
                        "lower price, which increases quantity demanded and decreases quantity supplied, until the surplus is eliminated.",
                        "lower price, which decreases quantity demanded and increases quantity supplied, until the surplus is eliminated."
                    ],
                    "answer": "lower price, which increases quantity demanded and decreases quantity supplied, until the surplus is eliminated.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 33,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose roses are currently selling for $40 per dozen, but the equilibrium price of roses is $30 per dozen. We would expect a",
                    "options": [
                        "shortage to exist and the market price of roses to increase.",
                        "shortage to exist and the market price of roses to decrease.",
                        "surplus to exist and the market price of roses to increase.",
                        "surplus to exist and the market price of roses to decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "surplus to exist and the market price of roses to decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 34,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The current price of neckties is $30, but the equilibrium price of neckties is $25. As a result,",
                    "options": [
                        "the quantity supplied of neckties exceeds the quantity demanded of neckties at the $30 price.",
                        "the equilibrium quantity of neckties exceeds the quantity demanded at the $30 price.",
                        "there is a surplus of neckties at the $30 price.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 35,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A university's football stadium is never more than half-full during football games. This indicates",
                    "options": [
                        "the ticket price is above the equilibrium price.",
                        "the ticket price is below the equilibrium price.",
                        "the ticket price is at the equilibrium price.",
                        "nothing about the equilibrium price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the ticket price is above the equilibrium price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 36,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When the price of a good is lower than the equilibrium price,",
                    "options": [
                        "a surplus will exist.",
                        "buyers desire to purchase more than is produced.",
                        "sellers desire to produce and sell more than buyers wish to purchase.",
                        "quantity supplied exceeds quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "buyers desire to purchase more than is produced.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 37,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A shortage exists in a market if",
                    "options": [
                        "there is an excess supply of the good.",
                        "quantity supplied exceeds quantity demanded.",
                        "the current price is below its equilibrium price.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the current price is below its equilibrium price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 38,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a shortage exists in a market, then we know that the actual price is",
                    "options": [
                        "above the equilibrium price, and quantity supplied is greater than quantity demanded.",
                        "above the equilibrium price, and quantity demanded is greater than quantity supplied.",
                        "below the equilibrium price, and quantity demanded is greater than quantity supplied.",
                        "below the equilibrium price, and quantity supplied is greater than quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "below the equilibrium price, and quantity demanded is greater than quantity supplied.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 39,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If, at the current price, there is a shortage of a good, then",
                    "options": [
                        "sellers are producing more than buyers wish to buy.",
                        "the market must be in equilibrium.",
                        "the price is below the equilibrium price.",
                        "quantity demanded equals quantity supplied."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the price is below the equilibrium price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 40,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following would cause price to increase?",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in supply",
                        "a decrease in demand",
                        "a surplus of the good",
                        "a shortage of the good"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a shortage of the good",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 41,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When a shortage exists in a market, sellers",
                    "options": [
                        "raise price, which increases quantity demanded and decreases quantity supplied until the shortage is eliminated.",
                        "raise price, which decreases quantity demanded and increases quantity supplied until the shortage is eliminated.",
                        "lower price, which increases quantity demanded and decreases quantity supplied until the shortage is eliminated.",
                        "lower price, which decreases quantity demanded and increases quantity supplied until the shortage is eliminated."
                    ],
                    "answer": "raise price, which decreases quantity demanded and increases quantity supplied until the shortage is eliminated.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 42,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If there is a shortage of farm laborers, we would expect",
                    "options": [
                        "the wage of farm laborers to increase.",
                        "the wage of farm laborers to decrease.",
                        "the price of farm commodities to decrease.",
                        "a decrease in the demand for substitutes for farm labor."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the wage of farm laborers to increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 43,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose roses are currently selling for $20 per dozen, but the equilibrium price of roses is $30 per dozen. We would expect a",
                    "options": [
                        "shortage to exist and the market price of roses to increase.",
                        "shortage to exist and the market price of roses to decrease.",
                        "surplus to exist and the market price of roses to increase.",
                        "surplus to exist and the market price of roses to decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "shortage to exist and the market price of roses to increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 44,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Years ago, thousands of country music fans risked their lives by rushing to buy tickets for a Willie Nelson concert at Carnegie Hall. This behavior indicates",
                    "options": [
                        "the ticket price was above the equilibrium price.",
                        "the ticket price was below the equilibrium price.",
                        "the ticket price was at the equilibrium price.",
                        "nothing about the equilibrium price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the ticket price was below the equilibrium price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 45,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The law of supply and demand asserts that",
                    "options": [
                        "demand curves and supply curves tend to shift to the right as time goes by.",
                        "the price of a good will eventually rise in response to an excess demand for that good.",
                        "when the supply curve for a good shifts, the demand curve for that good shifts in response.",
                        "the equilibrium price of a good will be rising more often than it will be falling."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the price of a good will eventually rise in response to an excess demand for that good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 46,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-7. The equilibrium price and quantity, respectively, are",
                    "options": [
                        "$2 and 50 units.",
                        "$6 and 30 units.",
                        "$6 and 60 units.",
                        "$12 and 30 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$6 and 30 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 47,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-7. If the price were $8, a",
                    "options": [
                        "shortage of 20 units would exist, and price would tend to rise.",
                        "surplus of 25 units would exist, and price would tend to fall.",
                        "shortage of 25 units would exist, and price would tend to rise.",
                        "surplus of 45 units would exist, and price would tend to fall."
                    ],
                    "answer": "surplus of 25 units would exist, and price would tend to fall.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 48,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-7. If the price were $4, a",
                    "options": [
                        "surplus of 15 units would exist, and price would tend to fall.",
                        "shortage of 25 units would exist, and price would tend to rise.",
                        "surplus of 25 units would exist, and price would tend to fall.",
                        "shortage of 40 units would exist, and price would tend to rise."
                    ],
                    "answer": "shortage of 25 units would exist, and price would tend to rise.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 49,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-8. If only members are allowed to purchase tickets to this year's celebrity golf tournament, then what will be the equilibrium price?",
                    "options": [
                        "$10",
                        "$15",
                        "$20",
                        "$25"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$20",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 50,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-8. If both members and non-members are allowed to purchase tickets to this year's celebrity golf tournament, then what will be the equilibrium price?",
                    "options": [
                        "$10",
                        "$15",
                        "$20",
                        "$25"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$25",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 51,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-8. If both members and non-members are allowed to purchase tickets to this year's celebrity golf tournament and the country club sets the ticket price at $30, then there will be",
                    "options": [
                        "a shortage of 300 tickets.",
                        "a surplus of 300 tickets.",
                        "600 tickets sold.",
                        "600 tickets unsold."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a surplus of 300 tickets.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 52,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-8. If both members and non-members are allowed to purchase tickets to this year's celebrity golf tournament and the country club sets the ticket price at $20, then there will be",
                    "options": [
                        "a shortage of 300 tickets.",
                        "a surplus of 300 tickets.",
                        "300 tickets sold.",
                        "600 tickets unsold."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a shortage of 300 tickets.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 53,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-9. Regarding Harry and Darby, whose demand for sandwiches conforms to the law of demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "only Harry's",
                        "only Darby's",
                        "both Harry's and Darby's",
                        "neither Harry's nor Darby's"
                    ],
                    "answer": "both Harry's and Darby's",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 54,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-9. Regarding Harry and Darby, for whom are sandwiches a normal good?",
                    "options": [
                        "only for Harry",
                        "only for Darby",
                        "for both Harry and Darby",
                        "This cannot be determined from the given information."
                    ],
                    "answer": "This cannot be determined from the given information.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 55,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-9. Suppose x = 1. Then it must be true that",
                    "options": [
                        "Harry and Jake have the same income, which is lower than Darby's income.",
                        "if sandwiches and potato chips are complements for Harry, then those two goods are also complements for Jake.",
                        "Harry's demand curve is identical to Jake's demand curve.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Harry's demand curve is identical to Jake's demand curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 56,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-9. Suppose x = 1. Then the slope of the market demand curve is",
                    "options": [
                        "-3.",
                        "-1/3.",
                        "1/3.",
                        "3."
                    ],
                    "answer": "-1/3.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 57,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-9. Suppose Harry, Darby, and Jake are the only demanders of sandwiches. Also suppose x = 2. Then",
                    "options": [
                        "the slope of Jake's demand curve is -1/2, and the slope of the market demand curve is -5/2.",
                        "the slope of Jake's demand curve is -1/2, and the slope of the market demand curve is -2/5.",
                        "the slope of Jake's demand curve is -2, and the slope of the market demand curve is -5/2.",
                        "the slope of Jake's demand curve is -2, and the slope of the market demand curve is -2/5."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the slope of Jake's demand curve is -2, and the slope of the market demand curve is -2/5.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 58,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-9. Suppose Harry, Darby, and Jake are the only demanders of sandwiches and that the market demand violates the law of demand. Then, in the table, the value of x must be",
                    "options": [
                        "less than or equal to 5.",
                        "greater than or equal to 5.",
                        "greater than or equal to 7.",
                        "greater than or equal to 10."
                    ],
                    "answer": "greater than or equal to 7.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 59,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-9. Suppose Harry, Darby, and Jake are the only demanders of sandwiches. Also suppose the following: • x = 2. • The current price of a sandwich is $5.00. • The market quantity supplied of sandwiches is 10. • The law of supply applies to the supply of sandwiches. Then there is a",
                    "options": [
                        "shortage of 5 sandwiches, and the price would be expected to rise from its current level of $5.00.",
                        "shortage of 5 sandwiches, and the price would be expected to fall from its current level of $5.00.",
                        "surplus of 5 sandwiches, and the price would be expected to rise from its current level of $5.00.",
                        "surplus of 5 sandwiches, and the price would be expected to fall from its current level of $5.00."
                    ],
                    "answer": "surplus of 5 sandwiches, and the price would be expected to fall from its current level of $5.00.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 60,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-9. Suppose Harry, Darby, and Jake are the only demanders of sandwiches. Also suppose the following: • x = 2. • The current price of a sandwich is $3.00. • The market quantity supplied of sandwiches is 4. • The slope of the supply curve is 2. Then there is currently a",
                    "options": [
                        "shortage of 6 sandwiches, and the equilibrium price of a sandwich is less than $3.00.",
                        "shortage of 6 sandwiches, and the equilibrium price of a sandwich is $5.00.",
                        "surplus of 6 sandwiches, and the equilibrium price of a sandwich is less than $3.00.",
                        "surplus of 6 sandwiches, and the equilibrium price of a sandwich is $5.00."
                    ],
                    "answer": "shortage of 6 sandwiches, and the equilibrium price of a sandwich is $5.00.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 61,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 4-9. Suppose Harry, Darby, and Jake are the only demanders of sandwiches. Also suppose the following: • x = 2. • The current price of a sandwich is $3.00. • The market quantity supplied of sandwiches is 5. • The slope of the supply curve is 1. Then there is currently a",
                    "options": [
                        "shortage of 5 sandwiches, and the equilibrium price of a sandwich is between $3.00 and $5.00.",
                        "shortage of 5 sandwiches, and the equilibrium price of a sandwich is $5.00.",
                        "surplus of 5 sandwiches, and the equilibrium price of a sandwich is between $3.00 and $5.00.",
                        "surplus of 5 sandwiches, and the equilibrium price of a sandwich is $5.00."
                    ],
                    "answer": "shortage of 5 sandwiches, and the equilibrium price of a sandwich is between $3.00 and $5.00.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 62,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-14. At a price of",
                    "options": [
                        "$2, there is a surplus of 6 units.",
                        "$5, there is a surplus of 25 units.",
                        "$5, there is a shortage of $25.",
                        "$7, there is a surplus of 4 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$7, there is a surplus of 4 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 63,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-14. At a price of",
                    "options": [
                        "$2, there is a shortage of 6 units.",
                        "$5, there is a surplus of 25 units.",
                        "$5, there is a shortage of $25.",
                        "$7, there is a shortage of 4 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$2, there is a shortage of 6 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 64,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-14. At a price of",
                    "options": [
                        "$8, there is a surplus of 6 units.",
                        "$5, there is neither a shortage nor a surplus.",
                        "$2, there is a shortage of 6 units.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 65,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-15. Equilibrium price and quantity are, respectively,",
                    "options": [
                        "$15 and 200 units.",
                        "$25 and 600 units.",
                        "$25 and 400 units.",
                        "$35 and 200 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$25 and 400 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 66,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-15. At the equilibrium price,",
                    "options": [
                        "200 units would be supplied and demanded.",
                        "400 units would be supplied and demanded.",
                        "600 units would be supplied and demanded.",
                        "600 units would be supplied, but only 200 would be demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "400 units would be supplied and demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 67,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-15. At a price of $35, there would be a",
                    "options": [
                        "shortage of 400 units.",
                        "surplus of 200 units.",
                        "surplus of 400 units.",
                        "surplus of 600 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "surplus of 400 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 68,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-15. At a price of $35, there would be",
                    "options": [
                        "a shortage, and the price would tend to rise from $35 to a higher price.",
                        "a surplus, and the price would tend to rise from $35 to a higher price.",
                        "excess demand, and the price would tend to fall from $35 to a lower price.",
                        "excess supply, and the price would tend to fall from $35 to a lower price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "excess supply, and the price would tend to fall from $35 to a lower price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 69,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-15. At what price would there be an excess supply of 200 units of the good?",
                    "options": [
                        "$15",
                        "$20",
                        "$30",
                        "$35"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$30",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 70,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-15. At a price of $15, there would be a",
                    "options": [
                        "surplus of 400 units.",
                        "shortage of 200 units.",
                        "shortage of 400 units.",
                        "shortage of 600 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "shortage of 400 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 71,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-15. At a price of $20, there would be a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "shortage. The law of supply and demand predicts that the price will fall from $20 to a lower price.",
                        "surplus. The law of supply and demand predicts that the price will rise from $20 to a higher price.",
                        "excess demand. The law of supply and demand predicts that the price will rise from $20 to a higher price.",
                        "excess supply. The law of supply and demand predicts that the price will fall from $20 to a lower price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "excess demand. The law of supply and demand predicts that the price will rise from $20 to a higher price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 72,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-15. At what price would there be an excess demand of 200 units of the good?",
                    "options": [
                        "$15",
                        "$20",
                        "$30",
                        "$35"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$20",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 73,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-16. In this market, equilibrium price and quantity, respectively, are",
                    "options": [
                        "$10 and 30 units.",
                        "$10 and 50 units.",
                        "$10 and 70 units.",
                        "$4 and 50 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$10 and 50 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 74,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-16. If price in this market is currently $14, then there would be a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "surplus of 20 units. The law of supply and demand predicts that the price will rise from $14 to a higher price.",
                        "excess supply of 20 units. The law of supply and demand predicts that the price will fall from $14 to a lower price.",
                        "surplus of 40 units. The law of supply and demand predicts that the price will rise from $14 to a higher price.",
                        "excess supply of 40 units. The law of supply and demand predicts that the price will fall from $14 to a lower price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "excess supply of 40 units. The law of supply and demand predicts that the price will fall from $14 to a lower price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 75,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-16. If there is currently a shortage of 20 units of the good, then the law of",
                    "options": [
                        "demand predicts that the price will rise by $2 to eliminate the shortage.",
                        "supply predicts that the price will rise by $2 to eliminate the shortage.",
                        "supply and demand predicts that the price will rise by $2 to eliminate the shortage.",
                        "supply and demand predicts that the price will fall by $2 to eliminate the shortage."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply and demand predicts that the price will rise by $2 to eliminate the shortage.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 76,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-17. In this market, equilibrium price and quantity, respectively, are",
                    "options": [
                        "$15 and 400 units.",
                        "$20 and 600 units.",
                        "$25 and 500 units.",
                        "$25 and 800 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$20 and 600 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 77,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-17. At a price of $20, which of the following statements is not correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "The market is in equilibrium.",
                        "Equilibrium price is equal to equilibrium quantity.",
                        "There is no pressure for price to change.",
                        "The quantity of the good that is bought and sold is 600 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Equilibrium price is equal to equilibrium quantity.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 78,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-17. If price is $25, then quantity demanded and quantity supplied, respectively, are",
                    "options": [
                        "500 units and 500 units.",
                        "500 units and 800 units.",
                        "600 units and 600 units.",
                        "800 units and 500 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "500 units and 800 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 79,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-17. If the price is $25, then there would be an excess",
                    "options": [
                        "supply of 100 units, and price would fall.",
                        "supply of 300 units, and price would fall.",
                        "demand of 100 units, and price would fall.",
                        "demand of 300 units, and price would fall."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply of 300 units, and price would fall.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 80,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-17. If the price is $10, then there would be a",
                    "options": [
                        "shortage of 400 units, and price would rise.",
                        "surplus of 400 units, and price would rise.",
                        "shortage of 600 units, and price would rise.",
                        "surplus of 600 units, and price would rise."
                    ],
                    "answer": "shortage of 600 units, and price would rise.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 81,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-17. At a price of $15,",
                    "options": [
                        "quantity demanded exceeds quantity supplied.",
                        "there is a shortage.",
                        "there is an excess demand.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 82,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-18. What is the equilibrium price in this market?",
                    "options": [
                        "$0",
                        "$5",
                        "$7.50",
                        "$10"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$10",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 83,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-18. What is the equilibrium quantity in this market?",
                    "options": [
                        "5 units",
                        "7.5 units",
                        "10 units",
                        "The equilibrium quantity cannot be determined from this graph."
                    ],
                    "answer": "5 units",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 84,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-18. At a price of $12, there is a",
                    "options": [
                        "surplus of 1 unit.",
                        "surplus of 2 units.",
                        "shortage of 1 unit.",
                        "shortage of 2 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "surplus of 2 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 85,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-18. At a price of $4, there is a",
                    "options": [
                        "surplus of 3 units.",
                        "surplus of 6 units.",
                        "shortage of 3 units.",
                        "shortage of 6 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "shortage of 6 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 86,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You have been asked by your economics professor to graph the market for lumber and then to analyze the change that would occur in equilibrium price as a result of recent forest fires in the west. Your first step would be to",
                    "options": [
                        "decide which direction to shift the curve.",
                        "decide whether the fires affected demand or supply.",
                        "graph the shift to see the effect on equilibrium.",
                        "None of the above is correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decide whether the fires affected demand or supply.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 87,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following events must result in a higher price in the market for Snickers?",
                    "options": [
                        "Demand for Snickers increases, and supply of Snickers decreases.",
                        "Demand for Snickers and supply of Snickers both decrease.",
                        "Demand for Snickers decreases, and supply of Snickers increases.",
                        "Demand for Snickers and supply of Snickers both increase"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Demand for Snickers increases, and supply of Snickers decreases.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 88,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose buyers of computers and printers regard the two goods as complements. Then an increase in the price of computers will cause a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "decrease in the demand for printers and a decrease in the quantity supplied of printers.",
                        "decrease in the supply of printers and a decrease in the quantity demanded of printers.",
                        "decrease in the equilibrium price of printers and an increase in the equilibrium quantity of printers.",
                        "increase in the equilibrium price of printers and a decrease in the equilibrium quantity of printers."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in the demand for printers and a decrease in the quantity supplied of printers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 89,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following would increase in response to a decrease in the price of ironing boards?",
                    "options": [
                        "the quantity of irons demanded at each possible price of irons",
                        "the equilibrium quantity of irons",
                        "the equilibrium price of irons",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 90,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A decrease in input costs to firms in a market will result in a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "decrease in equilibrium price and an increase in equilibrium quantity.",
                        "decrease in equilibrium price and a decrease in equilibrium quantity.",
                        "increase in equilibrium price and a decrease in equilibrium quantity.",
                        "increase in equilibrium price and an increase in equilibrium quantity."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in equilibrium price and an increase in equilibrium quantity.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 91,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose there is an earthquake that destroys several corn canneries. Which of the following would not be a direct result of this event?",
                    "options": [
                        "Sellers would not be able to produce and sell as much as before at each relevant price.",
                        "The supply would decrease.",
                        "Buyers would not be willing to buy as much as before at each relevant price.",
                        "The equilibrium price would rise."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Buyers would not be willing to buy as much as before at each relevant price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 92,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An early frost in the vineyards of Napa Valley would cause a(n)",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in the demand for wine, increasing price.",
                        "increase in the supply of wine, decreasing price.",
                        "decrease in the demand for wine, decreasing price.",
                        "decrease in the supply of wine, increasing price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in the supply of wine, increasing price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 93,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose the number of buyers in a market increases and a technological advancement occurs also. What would we expect to happen in the market?",
                    "options": [
                        "Equilibrium price would decrease, but the impact on equilibrium quantity would be ambiguous.",
                        "Equilibrium price would increase, but the impact on equilibrium quantity would be ambiguous.",
                        "Equilibrium quantity would decrease, but the impact on equilibrium price would be ambiguous.",
                        "Equilibrium quantity would increase, but the impact on equilibrium price would be ambiguous."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Equilibrium quantity would increase, but the impact on equilibrium price would be ambiguous.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 94,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose the incomes of buyers in a market for a particular normal good decrease and there is also a reduction in input prices. What would we expect to occur in this market?",
                    "options": [
                        "Equilibrium price would decrease, but the impact on equilibrium quantity would be ambiguous.",
                        "Equilibrium price would increase, but the impact on equilibrium quantity would be ambiguous.",
                        "Equilibrium quantity would decrease, but the impact on equilibrium price would be ambiguous.",
                        "Equilibrium quantity would increase, but the impact on equilibrium price would be ambiguous."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Equilibrium price would decrease, but the impact on equilibrium quantity would be ambiguous.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 95,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What would happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of coffee if the wages of coffee-bean pickers fell and the price of tea fell?",
                    "options": [
                        "Price would fall, and the effect on quantity would be ambiguous.",
                        "Price would rise, and the effect on quantity would be ambiguous.",
                        "Quantity would fall, and the effect on price would be ambiguous.",
                        "Quantity would rise, and the effect on price would be ambiguous."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Price would fall, and the effect on quantity would be ambiguous.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 96,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following events would cause both the equilibrium price and equilibrium quantity of number two grade potatoes to increase if number two grade potatoes are an inferior good?",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in consumer income",
                        "a decrease in consumer income",
                        "greater government restrictions on agricultural chemicals",
                        "fewer government restrictions on agricultural chemicals"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in consumer income",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 97,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Beef is a normal good. You observe that both the equilibrium price and quantity of beef have fallen over time. Which of the following explanations would be most consistent with this observation?",
                    "options": [
                        "Consumers have experienced an increase in income, and beef-production technology has improved.",
                        "The price of chicken has risen, and the price of steak sauce has fallen.",
                        "New medical evidence has been released that indicates a negative correlation between a person's beef consumption and life expectancy.",
                        "The demand curve for beef must be positively sloped."
                    ],
                    "answer": "New medical evidence has been released that indicates a negative correlation between a person's beef consumption and life expectancy.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 98,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "During the last few decades in the United States, health officials have argued that eating too much beef might be harmful to human health. As a result, there has been a significant decrease in the amount of beef produced. Which of the following best explains the decrease in production?",
                    "options": [
                        "Beef producers, concerned about the health of their customers, decided to produce relatively less beef.",
                        "Government officials, concerned about consumer health, ordered beef producers to produce relatively less beef.",
                        "Individual consumers, concerned about their own health, decreased their demand for beef, which lowered the equilibrium price of beef, making it less attractive to produce.",
                        "Anti-beef protesters have made it difficult for both buyers and sellers of beef to meet in the marketplace."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Individual consumers, concerned about their own health, decreased their demand for beef, which lowered the equilibrium price of beef, making it less attractive to produce.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 99,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following events would unambiguously cause a decrease in the equilibrium price of cotton shirts?",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in the price of wool shirts and a decrease in the price of raw cotton",
                        "a decrease in the price of wool shirts and a decrease in the price of raw cotton",
                        "an increase in the price of wool shirts and an increase in the price of raw cotton",
                        "a decrease in the price of wool shirts and an increase in the price of raw cotton"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in the price of wool shirts and a decrease in the price of raw cotton",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 100,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following events would cause the price of oranges to fall?",
                    "options": [
                        "There is a shortage of oranges.",
                        "The FDA announces that bananas cause strokes, and oranges and bananas are substitutes.",
                        "The price of land throughout Florida decreases, and Florida produces a significant proportion of the nation's oranges.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The price of land throughout Florida decreases, and Florida produces a significant proportion of the nation's oranges.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 101,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What would happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of lattés if consumers' incomes rise and lattés are a normal good?",
                    "options": [
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would increase.",
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would increase, and the equilibrium quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would decrease, and the equilibrium quantity would increase."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 102,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If macaroni and cheese is an inferior good, what would happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of macaroni and cheese if consumers' incomes rise?",
                    "options": [
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would increase.",
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would increase, and the equilibrium quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would decrease, and the equilibrium quantity would increase."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 103,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If consumers often purchase muffins to eat while they drink their lattés at local coffee shops, what would happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of lattés if the price of muffins rises?",
                    "options": [
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would increase.",
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would increase, and the equilibrium quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would decrease, and the equilibrium quantity would increase."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 104,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If consumers often purchase muffins to eat while they drink their lattés at local coffee shops, what would happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of lattés if the price of muffins falls?",
                    "options": [
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would increase.",
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would increase, and the equilibrium quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would decrease, and the equilibrium quantity would increase."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 105,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If consumers view cappuccinos and lattés as substitutes, what would happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of lattés if the price of cappuccinos rises?",
                    "options": [
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would increase.",
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would increase, and the equilibrium quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would decrease, and the equilibrium quantity would increase."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 106,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If consumers view cappuccinos and lattés as substitutes, what would happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of lattés if the price of cappuccinos falls?",
                    "options": [
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would increase.",
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would increase, and the equilibrium quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would decrease, and the equilibrium quantity would increase."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 107,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If scientists discover that steamed milk, which is used to make lattés, prevents heart attacks, what would happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of lattés?",
                    "options": [
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would increase.",
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would increase, and the equilibrium quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would decrease, and the equilibrium quantity would increase."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 108,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What would happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of lattés if the cost of producing steamed milk, which is used to make lattés, rises?",
                    "options": [
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would increase.",
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would increase, and the equilibrium quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would decrease, and the equilibrium quantity would increase."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The equilibrium price would increase, and the equilibrium quantity would decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 109,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What would happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of lattés if coffee shops began using a machine that reduced the amount of labor necessary to produce them?",
                    "options": [
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would increase.",
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would increase, and the equilibrium quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would decrease, and the equilibrium quantity would increase."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The equilibrium price would decrease, and the equilibrium quantity would increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 110,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Saddle shoes are not popular right now, so very few are being produced. If saddle shoes become popular, then how will this affect the market for saddle shoes?",
                    "options": [
                        "The supply curve for saddle shoes will shift right, which will create a shortage at the current price. Price will increase, which will decrease quantity demanded and increase quantity supplied. The new market equilibrium will be at a higher price and higher quantity.",
                        "The supply curve for saddle shoes will shift right, which will create a surplus at the current price. Price will decrease, which will increase quantity demanded and decrease quantity supplied. The new market equilibrium will be at a lower price and higher quantity.",
                        "The demand curve for saddle shoes will shift right, which will create a shortage at the current price. Price will increase, which will decrease quantity demanded and increase quantity supplied. The new market equilibrium will be at a higher price and higher quantity.",
                        "The demand curve for saddle shoes will shift right, which will create a surplus at the current price. Price will decrease, which will increase quantity demanded and decrease quantity supplied. The new market equilibrium will be at a lower price and higher quantity."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The demand curve for saddle shoes will shift right, which will create a shortage at the current price. Price will increase, which will decrease quantity demanded and increase quantity supplied. The new market equilibrium will be at a higher price and higher quantity.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 111,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The market for diamond rings is closely linked to the market for high-quality diamonds. If a large quantity of high-quality diamonds enters the market, then the",
                    "options": [
                        "supply curve for diamond rings will shift right, which will create a shortage at the current price. Price will increase, which will decrease quantity demanded and increase quantity supplied. The new market equilibrium will be at a higher price and higher quantity.",
                        "supply curve for diamond rings will shift right, which will create a surplus at the current price. Price will decrease, which will increase quantity demanded and decrease quantity supplied. The new market equilibrium will be at a lower price and higher quantity.",
                        "demand curve for diamond rings will shift right, which will create a shortage at the current price. Price will increase, which will decrease quantity demanded and increase quantity supplied. The new market equilibrium will be at a higher price and higher quantity.",
                        "demand curve for diamond rings will shift right, which will create a surplus at the current price. Price will decrease, which will increase quantity demanded and decrease quantity supplied. The new market equilibrium will be at a lower price and higher quantity."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply curve for diamond rings will shift right, which will create a surplus at the current price. Price will decrease, which will increase quantity demanded and decrease quantity supplied. The new market equilibrium will be at a lower price and higher quantity.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 112,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Music compact discs are normal goods. What will happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of music compact discs if musicians accept lower royalties, compact disc players become cheaper, more firms start producing music compact discs, and music lovers experience an increase in income?",
                    "options": [
                        "Price will fall, and the effect on quantity is ambiguous.",
                        "Price will rise, and the effect on quantity is ambiguous.",
                        "Quantity will fall, and the effect on price is ambiguous.",
                        "Quantity will rise, and the effect on price is ambiguous."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Quantity will rise, and the effect on price is ambiguous.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 113,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What will happen to the equilibrium price of new textbooks if more students attend college, paper becomes cheaper, textbook authors accept lower royalties, and fewer used textbooks are sold?",
                    "options": [
                        "Price will rise.",
                        "Price will fall.",
                        "Price will stay exactly the same.",
                        "The price change will be ambiguous."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The price change will be ambiguous.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 114,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "New oak tables are normal goods. What would happen to the equilibrium price and quantity in the market for oak tables if the price of maple tables rises, the price of oak wood rises, more buyers enter the market for oak tables, and the price of the glue used in the production of the new oak tables increased?",
                    "options": [
                        "Price will fall, and the effect on quantity is ambiguous.",
                        "Price will rise, and the effect on quantity is ambiguous.",
                        "Quantity will fall, and the effect on price is ambiguous.",
                        "Quantity will rise, and the effect on price is ambiguous."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Price will rise, and the effect on quantity is ambiguous.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 115,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What would happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of peanut butter if the price of peanuts went up, the price of jelly fell, fewer firms decided to produce peanut butter, and health officials announced that eating peanut butter was good for you?",
                    "options": [
                        "Price will fall, and the effect on quantity is ambiguous.",
                        "Price will rise, and the effect on quantity is ambiguous.",
                        "Quantity will fall, and the effect on price is ambiguous.",
                        "Quantity will rise, and the effect on price is ambiguous."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Price will rise, and the effect on quantity is ambiguous.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 116,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Pens are normal goods. What will happen to the equilibrium price of pens if the price of pencils rises, consumers experience an increase in income, writing in ink becomes fashionable, people expect the price of pens to rise in the near future, the population increases, fewer firms manufacture pens, and the wages of pen-makers increase?",
                    "options": [
                        "Price will rise.",
                        "Price will fall.",
                        "Price will stay exactly the same.",
                        "The price change will be ambiguous."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Price will rise.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 117,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What will happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of traditional camera film if traditional cameras become more expensive, digital cameras become cheaper, the cost of the resources needed to manufacture traditional film falls, and more firms decide to manufacture traditional film?",
                    "options": [
                        "Price will fall, and the effect on quantity is ambiguous.",
                        "Price will rise, and the effect on quantity is ambiguous.",
                        "Quantity will fall, and the effect on price is ambiguous.",
                        "Quantity will rise, and the effect on price is ambiguous."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Price will fall, and the effect on quantity is ambiguous.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 118,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "New cars are normal goods. What will happen to the equilibrium price of new cars if the price of gasoline rises, the price of steel falls, public transportation becomes cheaper and more comfortable, auto-workers accept lower wages, and automobile insurance becomes more expensive?",
                    "options": [
                        "Price will rise.",
                        "Price will fall.",
                        "Price will stay exactly the same.",
                        "The price change will be ambiguous."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Price will fall.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 119,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What will happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of new cars if the price of gasoline rises, the price of steel rises, public transportation becomes cheaper and more comfortable, and auto-workers negotiate higher wages?",
                    "options": [
                        "Price will fall, and the effect on quantity is ambiguous.",
                        "Price will rise, and the effect on quantity is ambiguous.",
                        "Quantity will fall, and the effect on price is ambiguous.",
                        "Quantity will rise, and the effect on price is ambiguous."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Quantity will fall, and the effect on price is ambiguous.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 120,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Consider the market for new DVDs. If DVD players became cheaper, buyers expected DVD prices to fall next year, used DVDs became more expensive, and DVD production technology improved, then the equilibrium price of a new DVD would",
                    "options": [
                        "rise.",
                        "fall.",
                        "stay the same.",
                        "could rise, fall, or remain unchanged."
                    ],
                    "answer": "could rise, fall, or remain unchanged.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 121,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following sets of events must cause an increase in the price of a new house?",
                    "options": [
                        "higher wages for carpenters, higher wood prices, increases in consumer incomes, higher apartment rents, increases in population, and expectations of higher house prices in the future",
                        "lower wages for carpenters, lower wood prices, increases in consumer incomes, higher apartment rents, increases in population and expectations of higher house prices in the future",
                        "lower wages for carpenters, higher wood prices, decreases in consumer incomes, higher apartment rents, decreases in population and expectations of higher house prices in the future",
                        "higher wages for carpenters, lower wood prices, decreases in consumer incomes, lower apartment rents, decreases in population and expectations of lower house prices in the future"
                    ],
                    "answer": "higher wages for carpenters, higher wood prices, increases in consumer incomes, higher apartment rents, increases in population, and expectations of higher house prices in the future",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 122,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What would happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of lattés if coffee shops began using a machine that reduced the amount of labor necessary to produce steamed milk, which is used to make lattés, and scientists discovered that coffee prevents heart attacks?",
                    "options": [
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would increase.",
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would increase, and the effect on equilibrium quantity would be ambiguous.",
                        "The equilibrium quantity would increase, and the effect on equilibrium price would be ambiguous."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The equilibrium quantity would increase, and the effect on equilibrium price would be ambiguous.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 123,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What would happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of lattés if coffee shops began using a machine that reduced the amount of labor necessary to produce steamed milk, which is used to make lattés, and scientists discovered that lattés cause heart attacks?",
                    "options": [
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would increase.",
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would decrease, and the effect on equilibrium quantity would be ambiguous.",
                        "The equilibrium quantity would decrease, and the effect on equilibrium price would be ambiguous."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The equilibrium price would decrease, and the effect on equilibrium quantity would be ambiguous.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 124,
                    "topic": "Supply And Demand Together",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What would happen to the equilibrium price and quantity of lattés if the cost to produce steamed milk, which is used to make lattés, increased, and scientists discovered that lattés cause heart attacks?",
                    "options": [
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would increase.",
                        "Both the equilibrium price and quantity would decrease.",
                        "The equilibrium price would decrease, and the effect on equilibrium quantity would be ambiguous.",
                        "The equilibrium quantity would decrease, and the effect on equilibrium price would be ambiguous."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The equilibrium quantity would decrease, and the effect on equilibrium price would be ambiguous.",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        },
        "sector6": {
            "title": "Db",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 125,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-19. All else equal, an increase in the income of buyers who consider turkey to be an inferior good would cause a move from",
                    "options": [
                        "DA to DB.",
                        "DB to DA.",
                        "x to y.",
                        "y to x."
                    ],
                    "answer": "DA to DB.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 126,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-19. All else equal, a sale on chicken would cause a move from",
                    "options": [
                        "DA to DB.",
                        "DB to DA.",
                        "x to y.",
                        "y to x."
                    ],
                    "answer": "DA to DB.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 127,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-19. All else equal, the approach of Thanksgiving would cause a move from",
                    "options": [
                        "DA to DB.",
                        "DB to DA.",
                        "x to y.",
                        "y to x."
                    ],
                    "answer": "DB to DA.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 128,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-19. All else equal, buyers expecting turkey to be more expensive in the future would cause a current move from",
                    "options": [
                        "DA to DB.",
                        "DB to DA.",
                        "x to y.",
                        "y to x."
                    ],
                    "answer": "DB to DA.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 129,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-19. All else equal, a large number of people becoming vegetarians would cause a move from",
                    "options": [
                        "DA to DB.",
                        "DB to DA.",
                        "x to y.",
                        "y to x."
                    ],
                    "answer": "DA to DB.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 130,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-19. All else equal, the premature deaths of thousands of turkeys would cause a move from",
                    "options": [
                        "DA to DB.",
                        "DB to DA.",
                        "x to y.",
                        "y to x."
                    ],
                    "answer": "x to y.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 131,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-19. All else equal, an increase in the productivity of turkey farmers would cause a move from",
                    "options": [
                        "DA to DB.",
                        "DB to DA.",
                        "x to y.",
                        "y to x."
                    ],
                    "answer": "y to x.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 132,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-19. All else equal, a decrease in the price of the grain fed to turkeys would cause a move from",
                    "options": [
                        "DA to DB.",
                        "DB to DA.",
                        "x to y.",
                        "y to x."
                    ],
                    "answer": "y to x.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 133,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-19. All else equal, sellers expecting the price of turkey to rise in the future would cause a current move from",
                    "options": [
                        "DA to DB.",
                        "DB to DA.",
                        "x to y.",
                        "y to x."
                    ],
                    "answer": "x to y.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 134,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-20. All else equal, an increase in the price of the pulp used in the paper production process would cause a move from",
                    "options": [
                        "x to y.",
                        "y to x.",
                        "SA to SB.",
                        "SB to SA."
                    ],
                    "answer": "SB to SA.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 135,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-20. All else equal, sellers expecting the price of paper to decrease next month when many college students leave campuses for the summer would cause a current move from",
                    "options": [
                        "x to y.",
                        "y to x.",
                        "SA to SB.",
                        "SB to SA."
                    ],
                    "answer": "SA to SB.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 136,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-20. All else equal, a major paper manufacturer filing for bankruptcy and shutting down as a result of an IRS tax evasion investigation would cause a move from",
                    "options": [
                        "x to y.",
                        "y to x.",
                        "SA to SB.",
                        "SB to SA."
                    ],
                    "answer": "SB to SA.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 137,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-20. All else equal, an increase in the use of laptop computers for note-taking would cause a move from",
                    "options": [
                        "x to y.",
                        "y to x.",
                        "SA to SB.",
                        "SB to SA."
                    ],
                    "answer": "y to x.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 138,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-20. All else equal, buyers expecting paper to be more expensive in the future would cause a current move from",
                    "options": [
                        "x to y.",
                        "y to x.",
                        "SA to SB.",
                        "SB to SA."
                    ],
                    "answer": "x to y.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 139,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-20. All else equal, the return of college students to campus in the fall would cause a move from",
                    "options": [
                        "x to y.",
                        "y to x.",
                        "SA to SB.",
                        "SB to SA."
                    ],
                    "answer": "x to y.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 140,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-21. Which of the following movements would illustrate the effect in the market for golf balls of an increase in green fees?",
                    "options": [
                        "Point A to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point D",
                        "Point A to Point D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Point C to Point B",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 141,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-21. Which of the following movements would illustrate the effect in the market for paper napkins as a result of a \"Go Green\" advertising campaign encouraging people to use cloth napkins?",
                    "options": [
                        "Point A to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point D",
                        "Point A to Point D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Point C to Point B",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 142,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-21. Which of the following movements would illustrate the effect in the market for orange juice of an announcement by the American Dental Association that orange juice erodes tooth enamel?",
                    "options": [
                        "Point A to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point D",
                        "Point A to Point D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Point C to Point B",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 143,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-21. Which of the following movements would illustrate the effect in the market for swimming lessons of an increase in the incomes of parents with school-aged children?",
                    "options": [
                        "Point A to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point D",
                        "Point A to Point D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Point A to Point D",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 144,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-21. Which of the following movements would illustrate the effect in the market for Ramen noodles of a decrease in the incomes of young adults, assuming that Ramen noodles are an inferior good?",
                    "options": [
                        "Point A to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point D",
                        "Point A to Point D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Point A to Point D",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 145,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-21. Which of the following movements would illustrate the effect in the market for ballroom dancing lessons resulting from the introduction of a popular new television show called \"Dancing with the Stars\"?",
                    "options": [
                        "Point A to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point D",
                        "Point A to Point D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Point A to Point D",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 146,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-21. Which of the following movements would illustrate the effect in the market for bread of an increase in the price of flour?",
                    "options": [
                        "Point A to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point D",
                        "Point A to Point D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Point C to Point D",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 147,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-21. Which of the following movements would illustrate the effect in the market for kitchen cabinets of an increase in the price of wood?",
                    "options": [
                        "Point A to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point D",
                        "Point A to Point D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Point C to Point D",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 148,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-21. Which of the following movements would illustrate the effect in the market for wedding cakes resulting from a decrease in the price number of pastry chefs?",
                    "options": [
                        "Point A to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point D",
                        "Point A to Point D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Point C to Point D",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 149,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-21. Which of the following movements would illustrate the effect in the market for chocolate chip cookies of an improved high-speed mixer that allows bakers to produce cookies in less time?",
                    "options": [
                        "Point A to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point D",
                        "Point A to Point D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Point A to Point B",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 150,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-21. Which of the following movements would illustrate the effect in the market for chocolate chip cookies of a decrease in the price of flour?",
                    "options": [
                        "Point A to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point D",
                        "Point A to Point D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Point A to Point B",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 151,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-21. Which of the following movements would illustrate the effect in the market for doctor's visits of an increase in the number of medical students graduating from medical school and successfully completing their residency programs?",
                    "options": [
                        "Point A to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point B",
                        "Point C to Point D",
                        "Point A to Point D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Point A to Point B",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 152,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-22. Panel (a) shows which of the following?",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in demand and an increase in quantity supplied",
                        "an increase in demand and an increase in supply",
                        "an increase in quantity demanded and an increase in quantity supplied",
                        "an increase in quantity demanded and an increase in supply"
                    ],
                    "answer": "an increase in demand and an increase in quantity supplied",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 153,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-22. Panel (b) shows which of the following?",
                    "options": [
                        "a decrease in demand and a decrease in quantity supplied",
                        "a decrease in demand and a decrease in supply",
                        "a decrease in quantity demanded and a decrease in quantity supplied",
                        "a decrease in quantity demanded and a decrease in supply"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in demand and a decrease in quantity supplied",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 154,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-22. Panel (c) shows which of the following?",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in demand and an increase in quantity supplied",
                        "an increase in demand and an increase in supply",
                        "an increase in quantity demanded and an increase in quantity supplied",
                        "an increase in quantity demanded and an increase in supply"
                    ],
                    "answer": "an increase in quantity demanded and an increase in supply",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 155,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-22. Panel (d) shows which of the following?",
                    "options": [
                        "a decrease in demand and a decrease in quantity supplied",
                        "a decrease in demand and a decrease in supply",
                        "a decrease in quantity demanded and a decrease in quantity supplied",
                        "a decrease in quantity demanded and a decrease in supply"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in quantity demanded and a decrease in supply",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 156,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-22. Which of the four panels illustrates a decrease in quantity demanded?",
                    "options": [
                        "Panel (a)",
                        "Panel (b)",
                        "Panel (c)",
                        "Panel (d)"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Panel (d)",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 157,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-22. Which of the four panels illustrates an increase in quantity demanded?",
                    "options": [
                        "Panel (a)",
                        "Panel (b)",
                        "Panel (c)",
                        "Panel (d)"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Panel (c)",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 158,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-22. Which of the four panels illustrates a decrease in quantity supplied?",
                    "options": [
                        "Panel (a)",
                        "Panel (b)",
                        "Panel (c)",
                        "Panel (d)"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Panel (b)",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 159,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-22. Which of the four panels illustrates an increase in quantity supplied?",
                    "options": [
                        "Panel (a)",
                        "Panel (b)",
                        "Panel (c)",
                        "Panel (d)"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Panel (a)",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 160,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-22. Which of the four panels represents the market for pizza delivery in a college town as we go from summer to the beginning of the fall semester?",
                    "options": [
                        "Panel (a)",
                        "Panel (b)",
                        "Panel (c)",
                        "Panel (d)"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Panel (a)",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 161,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-22 Which of the four panels represents the market for winter coats as we progress from winter to spring?",
                    "options": [
                        "Panel (a)",
                        "Panel (b)",
                        "Panel (c)",
                        "Panel (d)"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Panel (b)",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 162,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-22. Which of the four panels represents the market for cars as a result of the adoption of new technology on assembly lines?",
                    "options": [
                        "Panel (a)",
                        "Panel (b)",
                        "Panel (c)",
                        "Panel (d)"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Panel (c)",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 163,
                    "topic": "Db",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 4-22. Which of the four panels represents the market for peanut butter after a major hurricane hits the peanut-growing south?",
                    "options": [
                        "Panel (a)",
                        "Panel (b)",
                        "Panel (c)",
                        "Panel (d)"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Panel (d)",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        },
        "sector7": {
            "title": "Conclusion",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "Conclusion",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In any economic system, scarce resources have to be allocated among competing uses. Market economies harness the forces of",
                    "options": [
                        "government to allocate scarce resources.",
                        "supply and demand to allocate scarce resources.",
                        "credit cards to allocate scarce resources.",
                        "nature to allocate scarce resources."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply and demand to allocate scarce resources.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "Conclusion",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The signals that guide the allocation of resources in a market economy are",
                    "options": [
                        "surpluses and shortages.",
                        "quantities.",
                        "government policies.",
                        "prices."
                    ],
                    "answer": "prices.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "Conclusion",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Who gets scarce resources in a market economy?",
                    "options": [
                        "the government",
                        "whoever the government decides gets them",
                        "whoever wants them",
                        "whoever is willing and able to pay the price"
                    ],
                    "answer": "whoever is willing and able to pay the price",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "Conclusion",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "There is no shortage of scarce resources in a market economy because",
                    "options": [
                        "the government makes shortages illegal.",
                        "resources are abundant in market economies.",
                        "prices adjust to eliminate shortages.",
                        "quantity supplied is always greater than quantity demanded in market economies."
                    ],
                    "answer": "prices adjust to eliminate shortages.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "Conclusion",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In a market economy, who or what determines who produces each good and how much is produced?",
                    "options": [
                        "the government",
                        "lawyers",
                        "lotteries",
                        "prices"
                    ],
                    "answer": "prices",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "Conclusion",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of these statements does not apply to market economies?",
                    "options": [
                        "Prices prevent decentralized decision making from degenerating into chaos.",
                        "Prices coordinate the actions of millions of people with varying abilities and desires.",
                        "Prices ensure that anyone who wants a product can get it.",
                        "Prices ensure that what needs to get done does in fact get done."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Prices ensure that anyone who wants a product can get it.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "Conclusion",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose the United States had a short-term shortage of farmers. Which mechanisms would adjust to remove the shortage?",
                    "options": [
                        "The government would provide tax incentives to encourage people to become farmers.",
                        "The government would subsidize the production of food.",
                        "The prices of food and the wages of farmers would adjust.",
                        "There are no mechanisms to remove the shortage."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The prices of food and the wages of farmers would adjust.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 8,
                    "topic": "Conclusion",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Adam Smith suggested that an invisible had guides market economies. In this analogy, what is the baton that the invisible hand uses to conduct the economic orchestra?",
                    "options": [
                        "the government",
                        "prices",
                        "subsidies",
                        "the Federal Reserve"
                    ],
                    "answer": "prices",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        }
    }
}
